<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Intune on Systems Management Squad</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/categories/intune/</link><description>Recent content in Intune on Systems Management Squad</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2023 08:59:20 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sysmansquad.com/categories/intune/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Mystery of Required Reboots during Autopilot</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2023/03/30/mystery-of-required-reboots/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2023 08:59:20 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2023/03/30/mystery-of-required-reboots/</guid><description>Businesses pay tens of thousands of $currency for Microsoft Partner consultants to come in, &amp;ldquo;modernise&amp;rdquo; their EUC estate, and leave behind a plethora of bugs and issues that shouldn&amp;rsquo;t exist because said partners are supposed to be &amp;ldquo;industry experts&amp;rdquo;.
Completely unrelated, an issue I was working on at a client was with their Autopilot setup left behind from an MS partner that was causing a forced reboot mid-ESP. Shortly after entering company credentials, there would be a 10 minute reboot warning and no way to cancel - other than Shift+F10 and running shutdown -a which a normal end user wouldn&amp;rsquo;t know and shouldn&amp;rsquo;t need to know.</description></item><item><title>Moving away from software center to company portal</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2023/03/10/moving-away-from-software-center-to-company-portal/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2023/03/10/moving-away-from-software-center-to-company-portal/</guid><description>The elevator pitch You want to move your apps from configuration manager to Intune, but you need to keep the configuration manager client on your devices for various other reasons that have nothing to do with apps.
If you have switched the co-management workload over to intune, the apps in configuration manager will be visible in both software center and company portal, so how do you signal to your users to use the company portal going forward?</description></item><item><title>Microphone App Permissions</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2023/01/21/microphone_app_permissions/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2023 13:59:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2023/01/21/microphone_app_permissions/</guid><description>Where is mike? User reports that voice calls in teams no longer worked. The user claimed that he hadn&amp;rsquo;t changed anything. Leaving us to figure this out ourselves, so we did the usual troubleshooting, trying a new headset, trying to use the browser based teams client.
eventually we stumbled upon the culprit, we looked at the microphone settings under the &amp;ldquo;Security &amp;amp; Privacy&amp;rdquo; section in the Windows 11 settings app: unmanaged, but the user had manually disabled the microphone permissions for win32 apps the user had some how flipped the switch for &amp;ldquo;Let desktop apps access your microphone&amp;rdquo; to off, effectively disabling all microphone access for all win32 based apps on the system (which is why teams app and teams in browser stopped working)</description></item><item><title>Who Is Logged On, From The System Context</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2022/08/09/which-user-is-logged-in-when-running-as-system/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 13:59:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2022/08/09/which-user-is-logged-in-when-running-as-system/</guid><description>Intro Have you ever deployed a script that needs to be executed in the system context, but you also need to work with something that is currently running in the user context?
Obviously you could just loop through all the user profiles on the system, but thats not always a good idea.
Lo and behold, you can simply see who is the owner of the explorer.exe process and use that, Obviously this will not work if no one is logged on.</description></item><item><title>Removing The Built-in Teams App in Windows 11 with Intune</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/10/08/removing-the-built-in-teams-app-in-windows-11-with-intune/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Oct 2021 13:59:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/10/08/removing-the-built-in-teams-app-in-windows-11-with-intune/</guid><description>Intro So you&amp;rsquo;ve started rolling out Windows 11 to your endpoints, and your users got confused and upset over the consumer teams apps that is installed? Understandably you wish to do something about this.
(╯°□°）╯︵ ┻━┻ No worries mate, Intune Proactive Remediations to the rescue!
The Solution The code below fixes two things.
It removes the chat by writing the registry key that disables it
the TaskbarMn DWORD controls this Then it simply uninstalls the appx package for the consumer teams app, note that this has no effect on the regular teams app.</description></item><item><title>Setting Environmental Variables with Intune and proactive remediations</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/07/02/setting-environmental-variables-with-intune-and-proactive-remediations/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 05:24:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/07/02/setting-environmental-variables-with-intune-and-proactive-remediations/</guid><description>As you may have noticed by now, there doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to be any nice built in way to set environmental variables in intune 🙁
The Problem Setting a user environmental variable using powershell is an easy task to accomplish, you basically just run the following:
1 Set-ItemProperty -Path HKCU:\Environment -Name temp -Value &amp;#34;c:\temp\&amp;#34; This works just fine, but won&amp;rsquo;t take effect until the user either reboots or signs into the device again.</description></item><item><title>Setting A Default Outlook Signature in Outlook using Intune Proactive Remediations</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/06/18/setting-a-default-outlook-signature-in-outlook-using-intune-proactive-remediations/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 12:37:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/06/18/setting-a-default-outlook-signature-in-outlook-using-intune-proactive-remediations/</guid><description>So you have already figured out how to dynamically generated outlook signatures, but now you want to make sure that people actually use them. but without preventing the use of other signatures your users might have.
Well it just so happens that I have a solution for you!
No default signature has been set
To do all this, we create a new Proactive Remediation in Intune.
Add the detection and remediations scripts from below, and set it to run as the user.</description></item><item><title>Working around NPS limitations for AADJ Windows devices</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/04/27/working-around-nps-limitations-for-aadj-windows-devices/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 03:10:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/04/27/working-around-nps-limitations-for-aadj-windows-devices/</guid><description>⚠️ UPDATE (2023-03-11) ⚠️ Due to changes introduced by Microsoft in KB5014754 and being enforced on November 14, 2023, the name mapping method used in the scripts below will no longer work, and authentication will fail at that time. Thankfully, commenter Anders Hannus has pointed out a policy module named TameMyCerts for Microsoft Active Directory Certificate Services (AD CS). This policy module, used in conjunction with the below scripts, will let us work around Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s changes and give us the added benefit of no longer needing name mappings that are insecure.</description></item><item><title>Trigger Teams Installer for User After Machine Wide Installer</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/01/26/trigger-teams-installer-for-user-after-machine-wide-installer/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2021 12:30:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/01/26/trigger-teams-installer-for-user-after-machine-wide-installer/</guid><description>The Problem: Teams Machine Wide Installer finishes&amp;hellip; Then&amp;hellip; Nothing? Have you or a loved one ever deployed Microsoft Teams in an enterprise environment? Did the users complain? Did project management complain? Management? You?
I&amp;rsquo;m sure someone was not happy about the overall user experience. In particular when the Teams Machine Wide installer is finished, and detected by your application management tool of choice it does&amp;hellip; nothing. The user is left with a message claiming Teams is &amp;lsquo;Installed&amp;rsquo; when clearly it is not.</description></item><item><title>Collecting Logs with Log Analytics for Intune devices</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/01/18/collecting-logs-with-log-analytics-for-intune-devices/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 17:38:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/01/18/collecting-logs-with-log-analytics-for-intune-devices/</guid><description>Why do I need logs? The purpose of this guide is to configure the collection of Logs in an Intune environment. By default the log analytics you enable in Intune does not give you much information beyond auditing basic things. With this approach we can record any desired log for all of our machines. There is a companion video for this setup https://youtu.be/Uw3GjMnSXbI.
Enabling Log Analytics Navigate to endpoint.microsoft.com Select Reports Select Diagnostic Settings Select Add Diagnostic setting Select all options under Log Select Send to Log Analytics workspace Select a Log Analytics workspace You can archive to a storage account to keep data longer Now that we have the log analytics workspace configured we can configure the Microsoft Monitoring Agent (MMA)</description></item><item><title>Mapping Network Drives on Intune Devices</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/12/16/mapping-network-drives-on-intune-devices/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2020 19:04:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/12/16/mapping-network-drives-on-intune-devices/</guid><description>This guide is part of a video series companion guide on setting up mapped drives on Intune devices - you can watch the video here S02E18 How to Map Network Drives on Microsoft Intune Devices - (I.T)! This is rather simple but I will be adding some useful bits of code for people who do not have an always on VPN solution for all those Work From Home scenarios.
Creating the script Before we get started let me explain how this process works.</description></item><item><title>Bulk Updating Autopilot enrolled devices with Graph API and assigning a Group Tag based on Purchase OrderID</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/08/24/bulk-updating-autopilot-enrolled-devices-with-graph-api-and-assigning-a-group-tag-based-on-purchase-orderid/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 14:31:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/08/24/bulk-updating-autopilot-enrolled-devices-with-graph-api-and-assigning-a-group-tag-based-on-purchase-orderid/</guid><description>The Problem For any new machines ordered from a vendor such as Dell that get enrolled into Autopilot you get the basic device info enrolled but nothing defining that would let it get auto-enrolled into a dynamic group easily. Purchase Order ID is included in every order we receive from Dell however I don&amp;rsquo;t want to have to add that Purchase Order ID into the dynamic device query every time a new machine gets added.</description></item><item><title>Setting ACL using Intune Endpoint Analytics Proactive Remediations</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/07/27/setting-acl-using-intune-endpoint-analytics-proactive-remediations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2020 14:56:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/07/27/setting-acl-using-intune-endpoint-analytics-proactive-remediations/</guid><description>Namaste y&amp;rsquo;all! In todays Siri dictated blog post, I will show you how you can configure access control lists (ACL) for a directory using Intune Proactive remediations.
The issue I was facing was that regular users do not have modify permissions to the public desktop on their corporate devices, meaning that the user is unable to remove annoying shortcuts that would get placed there by the various apps they install. While this is hardly a high priority task to solve.</description></item><item><title>Dynamic Outlook Email Signature Using with Intune Endpoint Analytics Proactive Remediations</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/07/08/dynamic-outlook-email-signature-using-with-intune-endpoint-analytics-proactive-remediations/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 03:09:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/07/08/dynamic-outlook-email-signature-using-with-intune-endpoint-analytics-proactive-remediations/</guid><description>Howdy y&amp;rsquo;all!
Since you have already read señor Shackelfords blog post on setting up Endpoint Analytics Proactive remediations, we can skip the intro and dive right in.
In this blog post we will be get familiar with a somewhat novel idea that proactive remediation&amp;rsquo;s can be used for. Which, as the title of this post suggests, is the creation of a dynamic email signature in the form of a .html file using Microsoft Graph.</description></item><item><title>Intune/Autopilot Proactive Remediation</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/07/07/intune-autopilot-proactive-remediation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 16:24:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/07/07/intune-autopilot-proactive-remediation/</guid><description>What is Proactive Remediation? Proactive remediations are a pair of scripts used to detect and remediate a problem on a machine. The first script runs a query on your endpoints that returns an exit code of success or failure. We call this first script the detection script. On a successful exit code it is reported as &amp;ldquo;Without issue&amp;rdquo; in the Intune portal and nothing else is executed. On a failed exit code the second script is run which is called a remediation script.</description></item><item><title>Intune/Autopilot Setup Companion Guide Part 2 – Windows Store for Business</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/01/27/intune-autopilot-setup-companion-guide-part-2-windows-store-for-business/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2020 19:15:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/01/27/intune-autopilot-setup-companion-guide-part-2-windows-store-for-business/</guid><description>Purpose The following blog posts will be a companion guide to Steve and Adam’s Intune training videos found at Intune.Training (this covers Episode 3) and will help you get the Windows Store for Business (WSfB, also known as Microsoft Store for Business) setup in your environment. This guide assumes that you already have followed Part 1 of this series and already have a working deployment profile. By the end of this guide you will have access to the Company Portal app and other apps of your choosing.</description></item><item><title>Intune/Autopilot Setup Companion Guide Part 1</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2019/12/18/autopilot-setup-part-1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2019 14:50:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2019/12/18/autopilot-setup-part-1/</guid><description>Purpose The following blog posts will be a companion guide to Steve and Adam&amp;rsquo;s Intune training videos found at Intune.Training (this covers Episode 1 and 2) and will help you get Autopilot going in your environment. This guide assumes that you already have office 365 and azure configured. By the end of this guide you will have a working bare bones Autopilot configuration. This has been a major request from several people in the WinAdmins community.</description></item></channel></rss>