<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Intune on Systems Management Squad</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/tags/intune/</link><description>Recent content in Intune on Systems Management Squad</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 00:14:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sysmansquad.com/tags/intune/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Dealing With Frontline Workers and OneDrive</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2023/04/11/Dealing-With-Frontline-Workers-OneDrive/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 00:14:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2023/04/11/Dealing-With-Frontline-Workers-OneDrive/</guid><description>OneDrive is an amazing product. It allows you to separate what&amp;rsquo;s important, the data, from the tools used to transform the data,the computer. Your CEOs laptop got dropped in a bathtub? No Problem. Hand them a laptop with Intune &amp;amp; Autopilot and they&amp;rsquo;ll be back up and running within an hour or so WITH all of their files. Despite it&amp;rsquo;s integral part to modern device management it has a few quirks that can make it a difficult product to administrate at times.</description></item><item><title>Microphone App Permissions</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2023/01/21/microphone_app_permissions/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2023 13:59:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2023/01/21/microphone_app_permissions/</guid><description>Where is mike? User reports that voice calls in teams no longer worked. The user claimed that he hadn&amp;rsquo;t changed anything. Leaving us to figure this out ourselves, so we did the usual troubleshooting, trying a new headset, trying to use the browser based teams client.
eventually we stumbled upon the culprit, we looked at the microphone settings under the &amp;ldquo;Security &amp;amp; Privacy&amp;rdquo; section in the Windows 11 settings app: unmanaged, but the user had manually disabled the microphone permissions for win32 apps the user had some how flipped the switch for &amp;ldquo;Let desktop apps access your microphone&amp;rdquo; to off, effectively disabling all microphone access for all win32 based apps on the system (which is why teams app and teams in browser stopped working)</description></item><item><title>Who Is Logged On, From The System Context</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2022/08/09/which-user-is-logged-in-when-running-as-system/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 13:59:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2022/08/09/which-user-is-logged-in-when-running-as-system/</guid><description>Intro Have you ever deployed a script that needs to be executed in the system context, but you also need to work with something that is currently running in the user context?
Obviously you could just loop through all the user profiles on the system, but thats not always a good idea.
Lo and behold, you can simply see who is the owner of the explorer.exe process and use that, Obviously this will not work if no one is logged on.</description></item><item><title>Removing The Built-in Teams App in Windows 11 with Intune</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/10/08/removing-the-built-in-teams-app-in-windows-11-with-intune/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Oct 2021 13:59:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/10/08/removing-the-built-in-teams-app-in-windows-11-with-intune/</guid><description>Intro So you&amp;rsquo;ve started rolling out Windows 11 to your endpoints, and your users got confused and upset over the consumer teams apps that is installed? Understandably you wish to do something about this.
(╯°□°）╯︵ ┻━┻ No worries mate, Intune Proactive Remediations to the rescue!
The Solution The code below fixes two things.
It removes the chat by writing the registry key that disables it
the TaskbarMn DWORD controls this Then it simply uninstalls the appx package for the consumer teams app, note that this has no effect on the regular teams app.</description></item><item><title>Working around NPS limitations for AADJ Windows devices</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/04/27/working-around-nps-limitations-for-aadj-windows-devices/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 03:10:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/04/27/working-around-nps-limitations-for-aadj-windows-devices/</guid><description>⚠️ UPDATE (2023-03-11) ⚠️ Due to changes introduced by Microsoft in KB5014754 and being enforced on November 14, 2023, the name mapping method used in the scripts below will no longer work, and authentication will fail at that time. Thankfully, commenter Anders Hannus has pointed out a policy module named TameMyCerts for Microsoft Active Directory Certificate Services (AD CS). This policy module, used in conjunction with the below scripts, will let us work around Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s changes and give us the added benefit of no longer needing name mappings that are insecure.</description></item><item><title>Signing and Deploying Applications via MSIX with Intune</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/09/15/signing-and-deploying-applications-via-msix-with-intune/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 17:22:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/09/15/signing-and-deploying-applications-via-msix-with-intune/</guid><description>Why would I want to use MSIX and what is it? MSIX is a Windows app package format that provides a modern packaging experience to all Windows apps. The MSIX package format preserves the functionality of existing app packages and/or install files in addition to enabling new, modern packaging and deployment features to Win32, WPF, and Windows Forms apps.
Do you have a bloated application? Maybe one or two that are so old it doesn&amp;rsquo;t even have any install parameters?</description></item></channel></rss>