<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Systems Management Squad</title><link>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/</link><description>Recent content on Systems Management Squad</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 12:34:34 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.sysmansquad.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>VPN Boundary Type and Understanding Its Options</title><link>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2020/09/14/vpn-boundary-type-and-understanding-its-options/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 12:34:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2020/09/14/vpn-boundary-type-and-understanding-its-options/</guid><description>Like many, I was very excited that the new Configuration Manager 2006 release included a huge improvement for remote devices by adding a new VPN Boundary type.
&amp;ldquo;Finally! I don&amp;rsquo;t have to constantly bug my Network Engineers as to which IP pools are being used for which VPN appliances.&amp;quot;
Create A New Boundary In the Admin Console, navigate to the Administration Node and open up Hierarchy Configuration and right-click on Boundaries</description></item><item><title>Allow OneDrive Syncing on AAD joined Devices</title><link>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2020/09/11/allow-onedrive-syncing-on-aad-joined-devices/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2020 17:23:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2020/09/11/allow-onedrive-syncing-on-aad-joined-devices/</guid><description>The Problem So I was walking on the beach and noticed that OneDrive wasn&amp;rsquo;t syncing anymore on my AzureAD joined laptop. I later learned that my endpoint administrator, Adam Gross, had enabled Allow syncing only on computers joined to specific domains in the OneDrive admin portal. which effectively blocked my AzureAD device 🙁
Which resulted in this message on my corporate device</description></item><item><title>Manage Distribution Point Content Using PSCMContentMgmt</title><link>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2020/09/04/manage-distribution-point-content-using-pscmcontentmgmt/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2020 21:59:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2020/09/04/manage-distribution-point-content-using-pscmcontentmgmt/</guid><description>Introduction I recently wrote PSCMContentMgmt which provides a simple and effective workflow for managing your MEMCM distribution points. Here are some of the things you can do with it:
Query content objects which are distributed to distribution point(s) or distribution point group(s) Compare content objects distributed to distribution point(s) or distribution point group(s) Find content objects in a &amp;ldquo;distribution failed&amp;rdquo; state for all or selective distribution points Remove, distribute or redistribute content objects returned by any function to distribution point(s) Find an object in your site by searching on any arbitrary ID (useful when reading logs and want to know what object an ID resolves to) Migrate a distribution point&amp;rsquo;s content to a new/different distribution point by exporting its content library to prestaged .</description></item><item><title>Getting Reboot History and Optimizing Legacy Functions</title><link>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2020/08/28/getting-reboot-history-and-optimizing-legacy-functions/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2020 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2020/08/28/getting-reboot-history-and-optimizing-legacy-functions/</guid><description>The other day, I logged on to a jump server and, while investigating an unrelated issue, I noticed the BG Info background showed the Last Reboot as March 1st, 2020. &amp;ldquo;That can&amp;rsquo;t be right,&amp;rdquo; I thought. &amp;ldquo;We have weekly maintenance windows to reboot these servers.&amp;rdquo;
As I opened an old stand-by function from my stash (originally posted here: https://gallery.technet.microsoft.com/scriptcenter/Get-RebootHistory-bc804819 in 2015) and ran it, I was a bit annoyed at how SLOW it was.</description></item><item><title>Enrolling and Autopiloting New and Pre-existing Devices into Intune with ConfigMgr – EDU</title><link>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2020/08/25/enrolling-and-autopiloting-new-and-pre-existing-devices-into-intune-with-configmgr-edu/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2020 15:45:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2020/08/25/enrolling-and-autopiloting-new-and-pre-existing-devices-into-intune-with-configmgr-edu/</guid><description>Months after we issued students and faculty 600+ unmanaged off the shelf laptops (no AD, no Azure AD, no Intune, no ConfigMgr) to get them off and running temporarily during this pandemic, my co-worker and I were tasked with figuring out how to bring these machines under some form of management. We did not have these machines in ConfigMgr or have the hardware hashes uploaded into Intune, so we had some work ahead of us.</description></item><item><title>Bulk Updating Autopilot enrolled devices with Graph API and assigning a Group Tag based on Purchase OrderID</title><link>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2020/08/24/bulk-updating-autopilot-enrolled-devices-with-graph-api-and-assigning-a-group-tag-based-on-purchase-orderid/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 14:31:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2020/08/24/bulk-updating-autopilot-enrolled-devices-with-graph-api-and-assigning-a-group-tag-based-on-purchase-orderid/</guid><description>The Problem For any new machines ordered from a vendor such as Dell that get enrolled into Autopilot you get the basic device info enrolled but nothing defining that would let it get auto-enrolled into a dynamic group easily. Purchase Order ID is included in every order we receive from Dell however I don&amp;rsquo;t want to have to add that Purchase Order ID into the dynamic device query every time a new machine gets added.</description></item><item><title>Setting ACL using Intune Endpoint Analytics Proactive Remediations</title><link>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2020/07/27/setting-acl-using-intune-endpoint-analytics-proactive-remediations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2020 14:56:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2020/07/27/setting-acl-using-intune-endpoint-analytics-proactive-remediations/</guid><description>Namaste y&amp;rsquo;all! In todays Siri dictated blog post, I will show you how you can configure access control lists (ACL) for a directory using Intune Proactive remediations.
The issue I was facing was that regular users do not have modify permissions to the public desktop on their corporate devices, meaning that the user is unable to remove annoying shortcuts that would get placed there by the various apps they install. While this is hardly a high priority task to solve.</description></item><item><title>Dynamic Outlook Email Signature Using with Intune Endpoint Analytics Proactive Remediations</title><link>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2020/07/08/dynamic-outlook-email-signature-using-with-intune-endpoint-analytics-proactive-remediations/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 03:09:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2020/07/08/dynamic-outlook-email-signature-using-with-intune-endpoint-analytics-proactive-remediations/</guid><description>Howdy y&amp;rsquo;all!
Since you have already read señor Shackelfords blog post on setting up Endpoint Analytics Proactive remediations, we can skip the intro and dive right in.
In this blog post we will be get familiar with a somewhat novel idea that proactive remediation&amp;rsquo;s can be used for. Which, as the title of this post suggests, is the creation of a dynamic email signature in the form of a .html file using Microsoft Graph.</description></item><item><title>Intune/Autopilot Proactive Remediation</title><link>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2020/07/07/intune-autopilot-proactive-remediation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 16:24:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2020/07/07/intune-autopilot-proactive-remediation/</guid><description>What is Proactive Remediation? Proactive remediations are a pair of scripts used to detect and remediate a problem on a machine. The first script runs a query on your endpoints that returns an exit code of success or failure. We call this first script the detection script. On a successful exit code it is reported as &amp;ldquo;Without issue&amp;rdquo; in the Intune portal and nothing else is executed. On a failed exit code the second script is run which is called a remediation script.</description></item><item><title>Modern BIOS Management with the Administration Service</title><link>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2020/06/18/modern-bios-management-with-the-administration-service/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2020 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2020/06/18/modern-bios-management-with-the-administration-service/</guid><description>2021-04-27 update: The solution now works over CMG. Please see this post for details.
If you haven&amp;rsquo;t seen my first blog post about modern driver management, the quick summary is that the solution uses packages created with the Driver Automation Tool and the administration service to retrieve information on these packages and identify the most suitable driver package to apply in a task sequence.
In this second part, I&amp;rsquo;ll be discussing the changes and improvements done to the existing solution to also dynamically retrieve and filter and apply BIOS updates.</description></item><item><title>Create Windows 10 Kiosk Environment</title><link>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2020/06/16/create-windows-10-kiosk-environment/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2020 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2020/06/16/create-windows-10-kiosk-environment/</guid><description>Recently I had case where a we had to deploy computers that required Kiosk mode. Trouble was, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t run Windows Kiosk mode for the auto start of the application I wanted the Kiosk users to operate.
I discovered these registry settings to allow me to functionally create a Kiosk environment.
These registry edits will result in the following:
Any time the user logs into this computer. The chosen application will launch.</description></item><item><title>Build a ConfigrMgr lab with AutomatedLab</title><link>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2020/06/15/build-a-configrmgr-lab-with-automatedlab/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2020/06/15/build-a-configrmgr-lab-with-automatedlab/</guid><description>In this post I&amp;rsquo;ll show you how to start building a ConfigMgr lab, for either Current Branch or Technical Preview, using AutomatedLab with Hyper-V. This approach is intended to be completely automated and &amp;ldquo;hands off&amp;rdquo; by calling a single script.
It downloads all the necessary files for you, including the CB or TP installation media. All you have to do is provide a Windows Server 2016/2019 ISO, but this can also be an evaluation copy.</description></item><item><title>Getting started with AutomatedLab</title><link>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2020/06/15/getting-started-with-automatedlab/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2020/06/15/getting-started-with-automatedlab/</guid><description>What is AutomatedLab? AutomatedLab is simply PowerShell module. In some ways it’s a framework because it encourages a particular workflow for managing named labs consisting of VMs with prefined applications / “roles” or custom roles.
The benefit using AutomatedLab is the simplicity it offers to quickly fire up and throw away environments, and rebuild again. It also offers a huge range of functions to build out whatever you want.
Generally, the workflow goes something like:</description></item><item><title>Working With Internet-Optimized Task Sequences and Generic Status Messages</title><link>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2020/06/10/working-with-internet-optimized-task-sequences-and-generic-status-messages/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2020/06/10/working-with-internet-optimized-task-sequences-and-generic-status-messages/</guid><description>For my customer the move to remote work is here to stay. In adjustment to the “New Normal,” deployment projects put on hold these last months are in discussion again. One project resuming soon is the upgrade from Office 2016 to Microsoft 365 Apps. With many laptop computers now internet or VPN-based what can be done to optimize upgrades for these remote users?
To provide background, my customer has recently implemented cloud management gateways and cloud distribution points.</description></item><item><title>Deploy languages via Software Center with PSCMWin10Language</title><link>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2020/06/08/deploy-languages-via-software-center-with-pscmwin10language/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2020/06/08/deploy-languages-via-software-center-with-pscmwin10language/</guid><description>This post complements my other post, where I walk-through the differences of LP, LIP, LXP and FoD.
Here I will show you how to use a PowerShell module I wrote, PSCMWin10Languages, to create Microsoft Endpoint Manager Configuration Manager Applications for each language you want to deploy via the Software Center.
These Applications are not for OSD. It changes the language only for the user who installs the Application via the Software Center.</description></item><item><title>Language Packs, Language Experience Packs, Language Interface Packs… what?!</title><link>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2020/06/08/language-packs-language-experience-packs-language-interface-packs-what/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2020/06/08/language-packs-language-experience-packs-language-interface-packs-what/</guid><description>For a while I have been curious on how to do Windows OSD with multiple languages &amp;ldquo;the proper way&amp;rdquo; using Configuration Manager. Whenever I have approached the subject I have always felt overwhelmed.
Googling the topic is just a hot mess. You&amp;rsquo;re faced with information that&amp;rsquo;s old, lacking real detail or generally misunderstood. My aim here is to demystify the topic and show you a solid way to do Windows 10 multi language OSD with ConfigMgr along with sound reasoning.</description></item><item><title>ARM (Azure Resource Manager) Templating for Windows Virtual Desktop</title><link>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2020/05/26/arm-azure-resource-manager-templating-for-windows-virtual-desktop/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2020 12:56:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2020/05/26/arm-azure-resource-manager-templating-for-windows-virtual-desktop/</guid><description>Why would I use ARM templating, isn&amp;rsquo;t the default Image Gallery fine? Well first off, what is ARM Templating? According to Microsoft &amp;ldquo;You can automate deployments and use the practice of infrastructure as code. In code, you define the infrastructure that needs to be deployed. The infrastructure code becomes part of your project. Just like application code, you store the infrastructure code in a source repository and version it&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;
What does all that mean?</description></item><item><title>NET-103 : Layering in Active Directory</title><link>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2020/05/19/net-103-layering-in-active-directory/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2020/05/19/net-103-layering-in-active-directory/</guid><description>Joe Ravi / CC BY-SA https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0
In previous articles, we&amp;rsquo;ve built the basic services you need without getting too far in the weeds. Now we&amp;rsquo;re going to layer in a central identity service.
It&amp;rsquo;s also hopefully going to be a lot shorter than previous articles, though I can&amp;rsquo;t make any promises - these things tend to all start small, then balloon rapidly.
If you&amp;rsquo;re continuing from NET-102 you&amp;rsquo;ll already have the following machines:</description></item><item><title>Modern Driver Management with the Administration Service</title><link>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2020/05/15/modern-driver-management-with-the-administration-service/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 14:39:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2020/05/15/modern-driver-management-with-the-administration-service/</guid><description>2021-04-27 update: The solution now works over CMG. Please see this post for details.
Hello!
Today I’d like to share with you a new solution I’ve developed to allow me to use the free Modern Driver Management solution from the team at MSEndpointMgr at my work. My goal is to use the process developed by them for managing drivers in a task sequence and convert it to use the ConfigMgr Administration Service since my company won&amp;rsquo;t allow me to install their third-party web service.</description></item><item><title>Sharing Google Meet Links With Students Safely Can Be Confusing For I.T. Pros, Let Alone Teachers</title><link>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2020/04/26/sharing-google-meet-links-with-students-safely/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 20:26:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2020/04/26/sharing-google-meet-links-with-students-safely/</guid><description>TL;DR: Classroom-Meet integrated meeting links are safe. Nickname Meet meeting links are safe. Blank/Non-Nickname Meet meeting links ARE NOT safe. Calendar generated Meet meeting links ARE NOT safe. I&amp;rsquo;ll start by saying that I recognize COVID-19 and it&amp;rsquo;s impact on technology use in K-12 public education put many of us in a position of building the airplane as we&amp;rsquo;re flying on it. Administration, Curriculum and Technology have been working hard in school districts around the world to quickly train and support staff and faculty using systems they may never have heard of before this situation.</description></item><item><title>Teams Channel Notification when OSD Fails</title><link>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2020/04/22/teams-channel-notification-when-osd-fails/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2020/04/22/teams-channel-notification-when-osd-fails/</guid><description>How would you like this lovely notification appearing within MS Teams every time a build failed? Better than getting a helpdesk ticket or not finding out at all.
Well, now you can!
Removed broken screenshot - editor
Step 1 - Configure Teams You need to make sure your O365 Administrator has enabled Incoming webhooks connectors in your O365 Tenant.
Open Teams. Select a channel, or create a new channel specific for these notifications (This is best practice so normal channels are not spammed) Click the &amp;hellip; Next to the channel name and choose Connectors Removed broken screenshot - editor</description></item><item><title>Collect Client Logs – The Fast Channel Way</title><link>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2020/04/08/collect-client-logs-the-fast-channel-way/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2020/04/08/collect-client-logs-the-fast-channel-way/</guid><description>What&amp;rsquo;s New? Starting in MEMCM 2002 there is an incredible new tool in the Client Notification tool bag. Client log collection!
This is a vital addition to the console. At first glance I thought&amp;hellip;
But then the features full value was realized!
Collecting Logs Over CMG Scenario: Increasing remote workforce, no VPN, but that nifty CMG thing is in place. What does that imply? There is no SMB access to the client.</description></item><item><title>Inventory Deprovisioned Windows 10 Apps</title><link>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2020/03/11/inventory-deprovisioned-windows-10-apps/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2020 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2020/03/11/inventory-deprovisioned-windows-10-apps/</guid><description>In my previous post I&amp;rsquo;ve shown that we can revert the deprovisioning of Windows 10 apps. This is awesome news for anyone that has removed the Windows Store. I have been unable to find any other way of restoring the Windows Store once it has been deprovisioned, so this is an awesome time saver. Instead of reimaging devices that do not have the store we can simply &amp;lsquo;reprovision&amp;rsquo; the store, and perform a feature update!</description></item><item><title>Managing Multiple Office 365 Deployments with ConfigMgr</title><link>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2021/02/25/managing-multiple-office-365-deployments-with-configmgr/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2020 17:36:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2021/02/25/managing-multiple-office-365-deployments-with-configmgr/</guid><description>At the client I&amp;rsquo;m currently working for, we have FIVE different deployments of Office 365 Client within Microsoft Enterprise Configuration Manager. The business decided that they only wanted users to have exactly what was needed. Essentially, this is the legacy approach to Office deployment in the MSI days where you could fully customise which components were installed and was easy to add bits back in at a later date.
These are the options they wanted:</description></item><item><title>To Trust Or Not To Trust (UNSIGNED DRIVERS): That Is The Question</title><link>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2021/02/04/to-trust-or-not-to-trust-unsigned-drivers-that-is-the-question/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 06:48:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2021/02/04/to-trust-or-not-to-trust-unsigned-drivers-that-is-the-question/</guid><description>This post is intended to help others who might want to better understand why their Operating System Deployment (OSD) task sequence (TS) is failing during the Setup Windows and Configuration Manager step with an error code of 0x80004005 and how to identify the unsigned drivers in your driver package that might be causing it. Maybe my google-fu was failing me, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t see anything else out there that was a guided tour with pictures through the old Microsoft article on this issue.</description></item><item><title>Intune/Autopilot Setup Companion Guide Part 2 – Windows Store for Business</title><link>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2021/01/27/intune-autopilot-setup-companion-guide-part-2-windows-store-for-business/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2020 19:15:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2021/01/27/intune-autopilot-setup-companion-guide-part-2-windows-store-for-business/</guid><description>Purpose The following blog posts will be a companion guide to Steve and Adam’s Intune training videos found at Intune.Training (this covers Episode 3) and will help you get the Windows Store for Business (WSfB, also known as Microsoft Store for Business) setup in your environment. This guide assumes that you already have followed Part 1 of this series and already have a working deployment profile. By the end of this guide you will have access to the Company Portal app and other apps of your choosing.</description></item><item><title>NET-102: Build your lab</title><link>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2021/01/23/net-102-build-your-lab/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2020 07:13:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2021/01/23/net-102-build-your-lab/</guid><description>Welcome back! We&amp;rsquo;re now going to move on to the actual effort it takes to build your lab. As you recall we got pretty far last time in documenting the beginnings of our network. For this lab I&amp;rsquo;ll be using VMWare Workstation, but you can accomplish this with Microsoft Hyper-V, Oracle VirtualBox, the free tier of VMWare&amp;rsquo;s ESX, or XCP-NG.
If you haven&amp;rsquo;t read the previous post, please have a look here as each post builds upon the last.</description></item><item><title>Windows Virtual Desktop: Creation and Management</title><link>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2021/01/13/wvd-creation-and-management/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 06:33:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2021/01/13/wvd-creation-and-management/</guid><description>THIS GUIDE IS NOW OUTDATED WITH THE RELEASE OF WVD 2.0, I will create a new blog with the updated info in the future! Some of the info below is still valid! Why Windows Virtual Desktop? Windows Virtual Desktop allows you to create virtual Windows 10 machines that can be accessed from virtually anywhere. This means you can give someone a full desktop experience from virtually anywhere including android and iOS!</description></item><item><title>Reprovision Windows 10 Apps… Wait, What?</title><link>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2021/01/06/reprovision-windows-10-apps-wait-what/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2020 13:54:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2021/01/06/reprovision-windows-10-apps-wait-what/</guid><description>Remember when we all complained that Microsoft &amp;ldquo;wasn&amp;rsquo;t respecting our app removals!&amp;rdquo; and they were all reinstalled during every feature update? Pepperidge farm remembers. Well, Microsoft was kind enough to hear our collective complaints, and take action on them. That is an awesome quality that we are seeing from the product teams at Microsoft.
Starting in Windows 10 1803, deprovisioned apps will NOT be reinstalled during a feature update. No more Solitaire returning from the dead every time we try to &amp;ldquo;Get current and stay current.</description></item><item><title>Intune/Autopilot Setup Companion Guide Part 1</title><link>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2019/12/18/autopilot-setup-part-1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2019 14:50:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2019/12/18/autopilot-setup-part-1/</guid><description>Purpose The following blog posts will be a companion guide to Steve and Adam&amp;rsquo;s Intune training videos found at Intune.Training (this covers Episode 1 and 2) and will help you get Autopilot going in your environment. This guide assumes that you already have office 365 and azure configured. By the end of this guide you will have a working bare bones Autopilot configuration. This has been a major request from several people in the WinAdmins community.</description></item><item><title>NET-101 : Create a Basic Lab Network – Design</title><link>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2019/12/17/net-101-create-a-basic-lab-network-design/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2019 06:59:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2019/12/17/net-101-create-a-basic-lab-network-design/</guid><description>As I go through my career, I often find that the answers I take for granted are not easy to find for people who are just starting out. I had the advantage of a dedicated class on network administration to build on, but not everyone had that opportunity. While this article focuses on a lab environment, most of the content will be applicable to real life as well.
I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to include as many reference links as possible to help you learn about the concepts involved, but I cannot explain everything in one article.</description></item><item><title>How to use modules and package providers during OSD with MECM (SCCM/MEMCM)</title><link>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2019/12/12/how-to-use-modules-and-package-providers-during-osd-with-mecm-sccm-memcm/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2019 15:53:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2019/12/12/how-to-use-modules-and-package-providers-during-osd-with-mecm-sccm-memcm/</guid><description>For the past few days, I&amp;rsquo;ve been implementing SnipeIT into our environment to start actually tracking assets as opposed to the archaic spreadsheet we had going. I wanted to add any new machine that were imaged into the database right away without any input from me. That way, all I had to do was assign a user to the device in the asset management portal for SnipeIT, and I was good to go.</description></item><item><title>Join The Squad</title><link>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/jointhesquad/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2019 01:18:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/jointhesquad/</guid><description>Join the Squad Fill out the form below and we will review and contact you to get you plugged into the Squad. Please be patient as we work out all of the bugs.
Placeholder for form</description></item><item><title>Meet the Squad</title><link>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/meetthesquad/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2019 20:11:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/meetthesquad/</guid><description>Aaron Glenn Admin/Mentor Aaron is a Sr. Systems Administrator from Tulsa, specializing in Microsoft technologies, with an emphasis on powershell.
Adam Cook Admin/Contributor Adam loves technology and helping people, focusing on PowerShell, Azure, ConfigMgr, and Linux.
Adam Gross Founder Adam is a Microsoft MVP in Enterprise Mobility and is the founder of SysManSquad
Andrew Arsenault Contributor Andrew is a systems administrator based out of Canada bringing some education sector experience to the blog.</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2019 06:00:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/about/</guid><description>Our core values We Foster Education If people aren&amp;rsquo;t learning from our efforts here, we are wasting our time. We want to enable people to learn by doing and by sharing what they know.
We Pursue Excellence We want to ensure that the community gets our best work. By having a team of mentors who can review content and coach contributors, we will produce top quality content for the community.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/authors/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/authors/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/drafts/2021-01-18-/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/drafts/2021-01-18-/</guid><description>S```Q```L```-SQL-```````````````SQL-S```Q```L``` SQLt```````````````SQLiS```Q```L```tSQLl```````````````SQLeS```Q```L```:SQL ```````````````SQLCS```Q```L```oSQLn```````````````SQLfS```Q```L```iSQLg```````````````SQLuS```Q```L```rSQLi```````````````SQLnS```Q```L```gSQL ```````````````SQLWS```Q```L```SSQLU```````````````SQLSS```Q```L``` SQLw```````````````SQLiS```Q```L```tSQLh```````````````SQL S```Q```L```SSQLC```````````````SQLCS```Q```L```MSQL ```````````````SQLCS```Q```L```uSQLr```````````````SQLrS```Q```L```eSQLn```````````````SQLtS```Q```L``` SQLB```````````````SQLrS```Q```L```aSQLn```````````````SQLcS```Q```L```hSQL ```````````````SQL(S```Q```L```SSQLe```````````````SQLrS```Q```L```vSQLe```````````````SQLrS```Q```L``` SQL2```````````````SQL0S```Q```L```1SQL6```````````````SQL)S```Q```L``` SQL–```````````````SQL S```Q```L```PSQLa```````````````SQLrS```Q```L```tSQL ```````````````SQLIS```Q```L``` SQLa```````````````SQLuS```Q```L```tSQLh```````````````SQLoS```Q```L```rSQL:```````````````SQL S```Q```L```RSQLi```````````````SQLcS```Q```L```hSQL ```````````````SQLMS```Q```L```aSQLw```````````````SQLdS```Q```L```sSQLl```````````````SQLeS```Q```L```ySQL ```````````````SQLtS```Q```L```ySQLp```````````````SQLeS```Q```L```:SQL ```````````````SQLpS```Q```L```oSQLs```````````````SQLtS```Q```L``` SQLd```````````````SQLaS```Q```L```tSQLe```````````````SQL:S```Q```L``` SQL-```````````````SQL0S```Q```L```0SQL1```````````````SQL-S```Q```L```1SQL1```````````````SQL-S```Q```L```3SQL0```````````````SQLTS```Q```L```0SQL0```````````````SQL:S```Q```L```0SQL0```````````````SQL:S```Q```L```0SQL0```````````````SQL+S```Q```L```0SQL0```````````````SQL:S```Q```L```0SQL0```````````````SQL S```Q```L```dSQLr```````````````SQLaS```Q```L```fSQLt```````````````SQL:S```Q```L``` SQLt```````````````SQLrS```Q```L```uSQLe```````````````SQL S```Q```L```uSQLr```````````````SQLlS```Q```L```:SQL ```````````````SQL/S```Q```L```?SQLp```````````````SQL=S```Q```L```1SQL0```````````````SQL9S```Q```L```1SQL ```````````````SQLcS```Q```L```aSQLt```````````````SQLeS```Q```L```gSQLo```````````````SQLrS```Q```L```iSQLe```````````````SQLsS```Q```L```:SQL ```````````````SQL S```Q```L``` SQL-```````````````SQL S```Q```L```ESQLn```````````````SQLdS```Q```L```pSQLo```````````````SQLiS```Q```L```nSQLt```````````````SQL S```Q```L```MSQLa```````````````SQLnS```Q```L```aSQLg```````````````SQLeS```Q```L```mSQLe```````````````SQLnS```Q```L```tSQL ```````````````SQL S```Q```L```-SQL-```````````````SQL-S```Q```L``` SQL#```````````````SQL S```Q```L```ISQLn```````````````SQLtS```Q```L```rSQLo```````````````SQLdS```Q```L```uSQLc```````````````SQLtS```Q```L```iSQLo```````````````SQLnS```Q```L``` SQL ```````````````SQLTS```Q```L```hSQLe```````````````SQLrS```Q```L```eSQL ```````````````SQLhS```Q```L```aSQLv```````````````SQLeS```Q```L``` SQLb```````````````SQLeS```Q```L```eSQLn```````````````SQL S```Q```L```sSQLo```````````````SQLmS```Q```L```eSQL ```````````````SQLgS```Q```L```rSQLe```````````````SQLaS```Q```L```tSQL ```````````````SQLgS```Q```L```uSQLi```````````````SQLdS```Q```L```eSQLs```````````````SQL S```Q```L```tSQLh```````````````SQLrS```Q```L```oSQLu```````````````SQLgS```Q```L```hSQL ```````````````SQLtS```Q```L```hSQLe```````````````SQL S```Q```L```ySQLe```````````````SQLaS```Q```L```rSQLs```````````````SQL S```Q```L```oSQLn```````````````SQL S```Q```L```cSQLo```````````````SQLnS```Q```L```fSQLi```````````````SQLgS```Q```L```uSQLr```````````````SQLiS```Q```L```nSQLg```````````````SQL S```Q```L```WSQLS```````````````SQLUS```Q```L```SSQL ```````````````SQLwS```Q```L```iSQLt```````````````SQLhS```Q```L``` SQLS```````````````SQLCS```Q```L```CSQLM```````````````SQL S```Q```L```fSQLr```````````````SQLoS```Q```L```mSQL ```````````````SQLtS```Q```L```hSQLe```````````````SQL S```Q```L```gSQLr```````````````SQLoS```Q```L```uSQLn```````````````SQLdS```Q```L``` SQLu```````````````SQLpS```Q```L```,SQL ```````````````SQLbS```Q```L```uSQLt```````````````SQL S```Q```L```ISQL ```````````````SQLfS```Q```L```eSQLl```````````````SQLtS```Q```L``` SQLi```````````````SQLtS```Q```L``` SQLw```````````````SQLaS```Q```L```sSQL ```````````````SQLtS```Q```L```iSQLm```````````````SQLeS```Q```L``` SQLf```````````````SQLoS```Q```L```rSQL ```````````````SQLmS```Q```L```eSQL ```````````````SQLtS```Q```L```oSQL ```````````````SQLaS```Q```L```dSQLd```````````````SQL S```Q```L```tSQLo```````````````SQL S```Q```L```tSQLh```````````````SQLeS```Q```L``` SQLl```````````````SQLiS```Q```L```bSQLr```````````````SQLaS```Q```L```rSQLy```````````````SQL S```Q```L```wSQLi```````````````SQLtS```Q```L```hSQL ```````````````SQLaS```Q```L```nSQL ```````````````SQLuS```Q```L```pSQLd```````````````SQLaS```Q```L```tSQLe```````````````SQLdS```Q```L``` SQLv```````````````SQLeS```Q```L```rSQLs```````````````SQLiS```Q```L```oSQLn```````````````SQL S```Q```L```tSQLo```````````````SQL S```Q```L```cSQLo```````````````SQLvS```Q```L```eSQLr```````````````SQL S```Q```L```SSQLe```````````````SQLrS```Q```L```vSQLe```````````````SQLrS```Q```L``` SQL2```````````````SQL0S```Q```L```1SQL6```````````````SQL,S```Q```L``` SQLa```````````````SQLnS```Q```L```dSQL ```````````````SQLpS```Q```L```aSQLr```````````````SQLtS```Q```L```iSQLc```````````````SQLuS```Q```L```lSQLa```````````````SQLrS```Q```L```lSQLy```````````````SQL S```Q```L```mSQLy```````````````SQL S```Q```L```pSQLe```````````````SQLrS```Q```L```sSQLo```````````````SQLnS```Q```L```aSQLl```````````````SQL S```Q```L```rSQLe```````````````SQLcS```Q```L```oSQLm```````````````SQLmS```Q```L```eSQLn```````````````SQLdS```Q```L```aSQLt```````````````SQLiS```Q```L```oSQLn```````````````SQLsS```Q```L``` SQLf```````````````SQLoS```Q```L```rSQL ```````````````SQLaS```Q```L``` SQLs```````````````SQLuS```Q```L```cSQLc```````````````SQLeS```Q```L```sSQLs```````````````SQLfS```Q```L```uSQLl```````````````SQL S```Q```L```ASQL-```````````````SQLZS```Q```L``` SQLs```````````````SQLeS```Q```L```tSQLu```````````````SQLpS```Q```L```.</description></item></channel></rss>