<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Azure on Systems Management Squad</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/categories/azure/</link><description>Recent content in Azure on Systems Management Squad</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sysmansquad.com/categories/azure/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Using PowerShell and Graph to update Azure AD user photos in bulk</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/12/03/2021-12-03-using-powershell-and-graph-to-update-azure-ad-user-photos-in-bulk/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/12/03/2021-12-03-using-powershell-and-graph-to-update-azure-ad-user-photos-in-bulk/</guid><description>Introduction In this post, I’ll give you some background information and show you how to utilize the Microsoft Graph API to bulk update Azure AD user photos. If you’d like to skip the background information and get straight to the nitty-gritty, click here.
Background I work at a private K-12 school in the United States. Like many schools out there, we have scheduled portraits once a year for students and staff.</description></item><item><title>Where is the report’s data??</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/05/15/where-is-the-reports-data/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 May 2021 03:21:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/05/15/where-is-the-reports-data/</guid><description>Have you ever looked at a report on a Portal Page and wanted to know just WHERE the data just came from?
Well you can - and finding the information can be so easy. Read on below to see how.
Introduction Take for example this report on a Proactive Remediation. I used one of the built in Proactive Remediations for the example, but it could easily be one of our other Proactive Remediation posts, like Dynamic Outlook Signatures, Building VPN Connections, or Repairing Folder permissions.</description></item><item><title>Collecting Logs with Log Analytics for Intune devices</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/01/18/collecting-logs-with-log-analytics-for-intune-devices/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 17:38:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/01/18/collecting-logs-with-log-analytics-for-intune-devices/</guid><description>Why do I need logs? The purpose of this guide is to configure the collection of Logs in an Intune environment. By default the log analytics you enable in Intune does not give you much information beyond auditing basic things. With this approach we can record any desired log for all of our machines. There is a companion video for this setup https://youtu.be/Uw3GjMnSXbI.
Enabling Log Analytics Navigate to endpoint.microsoft.com Select Reports Select Diagnostic Settings Select Add Diagnostic setting Select all options under Log Select Send to Log Analytics workspace Select a Log Analytics workspace You can archive to a storage account to keep data longer Now that we have the log analytics workspace configured we can configure the Microsoft Monitoring Agent (MMA)</description></item><item><title>Finding Azure Virtual Machines in Configuration Manager</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/01/05/finding-azure-virtual-machines-in-configuration-manager/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 05:04:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/01/05/finding-azure-virtual-machines-in-configuration-manager/</guid><description>A request came in from my System Admin group to push certain policies only to VMs hosted in Azure. Currently, they had a naming convention being used (well, supposed to be used) to simply prefix the hostname with AZ-, but they came across a couple Domain Controllers that hadn&amp;rsquo;t installed Updates in 7+ months, and of course the names didn&amp;rsquo;t follow the accepted standard.
So I started looking for ways to identify Azure devices definitively and came across this Detect Windows Azure Virtual Machine post, which led to reading the Azure Metadata Service docs, and eventually got me to turn this into a Configuration Item / Configuration Baseline and subsequent Device Collections.</description></item><item><title>Automating Outside of Business Hours Responses</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/12/30/automating-changing-out-of-business-hours-responses/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 19:20:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/12/30/automating-changing-out-of-business-hours-responses/</guid><description>Have you ever had customers emailing in outside of hours? In this post we will setup some scripted automatic maintenance of Auto-Reply responses on a user account.
We considered several possibilities but the customer did not have an Azure Subscription yet, we ended up using PowerShell, Microsoft Graph, App Authentication, and a Scheduled Task.
Our customer will be moving to Azure later so we will probably revisit this as Azure Functions, or possibly Power Automate later on.</description></item><item><title>Find Microsoft Accounts on Company Domains</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/11/23/find-microsoft-accounts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/11/23/find-microsoft-accounts/</guid><description>The other day I was helping someone over in the WinAdmins Discord. Their users kept getting confused about what their passwords were, and it was causing a lot of HelpDesk tickets. Let&amp;rsquo;s find out what users have Microsoft accounts on the company domain so we can help move those accounts elsewhere to streamline the user experience.
Update on Prevention: Microsoft has introduced some changes that at least seem to prevent NEW Microsoft Accounts on Company Domains.</description></item><item><title>Dynamic Outlook Email Signature Using with Intune Endpoint Analytics Proactive Remediations</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/07/08/dynamic-outlook-email-signature-using-with-intune-endpoint-analytics-proactive-remediations/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 03:09:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/07/08/dynamic-outlook-email-signature-using-with-intune-endpoint-analytics-proactive-remediations/</guid><description>Howdy y&amp;rsquo;all!
Since you have already read señor Shackelfords blog post on setting up Endpoint Analytics Proactive remediations, we can skip the intro and dive right in.
In this blog post we will be get familiar with a somewhat novel idea that proactive remediation&amp;rsquo;s can be used for. Which, as the title of this post suggests, is the creation of a dynamic email signature in the form of a .html file using Microsoft Graph.</description></item><item><title>ARM (Azure Resource Manager) Templating for Windows Virtual Desktop</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/05/26/arm-azure-resource-manager-templating-for-windows-virtual-desktop/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2020 12:56:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/05/26/arm-azure-resource-manager-templating-for-windows-virtual-desktop/</guid><description>Why would I use ARM templating, isn&amp;rsquo;t the default Image Gallery fine? Well first off, what is ARM Templating? According to Microsoft &amp;ldquo;You can automate deployments and use the practice of infrastructure as code. In code, you define the infrastructure that needs to be deployed. The infrastructure code becomes part of your project. Just like application code, you store the infrastructure code in a source repository and version it&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;
What does all that mean?</description></item><item><title>Intune/Autopilot Setup Companion Guide Part 2 – Windows Store for Business</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/01/27/intune-autopilot-setup-companion-guide-part-2-windows-store-for-business/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2020 19:15:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/01/27/intune-autopilot-setup-companion-guide-part-2-windows-store-for-business/</guid><description>Purpose The following blog posts will be a companion guide to Steve and Adam’s Intune training videos found at Intune.Training (this covers Episode 3) and will help you get the Windows Store for Business (WSfB, also known as Microsoft Store for Business) setup in your environment. This guide assumes that you already have followed Part 1 of this series and already have a working deployment profile. By the end of this guide you will have access to the Company Portal app and other apps of your choosing.</description></item><item><title>Windows Virtual Desktop: Creation and Management</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/01/13/wvd-creation-and-management/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 06:33:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/01/13/wvd-creation-and-management/</guid><description>THIS GUIDE IS NOW OUTDATED WITH THE RELEASE OF WVD 2.0, I will create a new blog with the updated info in the future! Some of the info below is still valid! Why Windows Virtual Desktop? Windows Virtual Desktop allows you to create virtual Windows 10 machines that can be accessed from virtually anywhere. This means you can give someone a full desktop experience from virtually anywhere including android and iOS!</description></item></channel></rss>