<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Proactive Remediation on Systems Management Squad</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/categories/proactive-remediation/</link><description>Recent content in Proactive Remediation on Systems Management Squad</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Oct 2021 13:59:21 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sysmansquad.com/categories/proactive-remediation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Removing The Built-in Teams App in Windows 11 with Intune</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/10/08/removing-the-built-in-teams-app-in-windows-11-with-intune/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Oct 2021 13:59:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/10/08/removing-the-built-in-teams-app-in-windows-11-with-intune/</guid><description>Intro So you&amp;rsquo;ve started rolling out Windows 11 to your endpoints, and your users got confused and upset over the consumer teams apps that is installed? Understandably you wish to do something about this.
(╯°□°）╯︵ ┻━┻ No worries mate, Intune Proactive Remediations to the rescue!
The Solution The code below fixes two things.
It removes the chat by writing the registry key that disables it
the TaskbarMn DWORD controls this Then it simply uninstalls the appx package for the consumer teams app, note that this has no effect on the regular teams app.</description></item><item><title>Setting Environmental Variables with Intune and proactive remediations</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/07/02/setting-environmental-variables-with-intune-and-proactive-remediations/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 05:24:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/07/02/setting-environmental-variables-with-intune-and-proactive-remediations/</guid><description>As you may have noticed by now, there doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to be any nice built in way to set environmental variables in intune 🙁
The Problem Setting a user environmental variable using powershell is an easy task to accomplish, you basically just run the following:
1 Set-ItemProperty -Path HKCU:\Environment -Name temp -Value &amp;#34;c:\temp\&amp;#34; This works just fine, but won&amp;rsquo;t take effect until the user either reboots or signs into the device again.</description></item><item><title>Setting A Default Outlook Signature in Outlook using Intune Proactive Remediations</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/06/18/setting-a-default-outlook-signature-in-outlook-using-intune-proactive-remediations/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 12:37:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/06/18/setting-a-default-outlook-signature-in-outlook-using-intune-proactive-remediations/</guid><description>So you have already figured out how to dynamically generated outlook signatures, but now you want to make sure that people actually use them. but without preventing the use of other signatures your users might have.
Well it just so happens that I have a solution for you!
No default signature has been set
To do all this, we create a new Proactive Remediation in Intune.
Add the detection and remediations scripts from below, and set it to run as the user.</description></item><item><title>Where is the report’s data??</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/05/15/where-is-the-reports-data/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 May 2021 03:21:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/05/15/where-is-the-reports-data/</guid><description>Have you ever looked at a report on a Portal Page and wanted to know just WHERE the data just came from?
Well you can - and finding the information can be so easy. Read on below to see how.
Introduction Take for example this report on a Proactive Remediation. I used one of the built in Proactive Remediations for the example, but it could easily be one of our other Proactive Remediation posts, like Dynamic Outlook Signatures, Building VPN Connections, or Repairing Folder permissions.</description></item><item><title>Mapping Network Drives on Intune Devices</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/12/16/mapping-network-drives-on-intune-devices/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2020 19:04:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/12/16/mapping-network-drives-on-intune-devices/</guid><description>This guide is part of a video series companion guide on setting up mapped drives on Intune devices - you can watch the video here S02E18 How to Map Network Drives on Microsoft Intune Devices - (I.T)! This is rather simple but I will be adding some useful bits of code for people who do not have an always on VPN solution for all those Work From Home scenarios.
Creating the script Before we get started let me explain how this process works.</description></item><item><title>Setting ACL using Intune Endpoint Analytics Proactive Remediations</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/07/27/setting-acl-using-intune-endpoint-analytics-proactive-remediations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2020 14:56:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/07/27/setting-acl-using-intune-endpoint-analytics-proactive-remediations/</guid><description>Namaste y&amp;rsquo;all! In todays Siri dictated blog post, I will show you how you can configure access control lists (ACL) for a directory using Intune Proactive remediations.
The issue I was facing was that regular users do not have modify permissions to the public desktop on their corporate devices, meaning that the user is unable to remove annoying shortcuts that would get placed there by the various apps they install. While this is hardly a high priority task to solve.</description></item><item><title>Dynamic Outlook Email Signature Using with Intune Endpoint Analytics Proactive Remediations</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/07/08/dynamic-outlook-email-signature-using-with-intune-endpoint-analytics-proactive-remediations/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 03:09:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/07/08/dynamic-outlook-email-signature-using-with-intune-endpoint-analytics-proactive-remediations/</guid><description>Howdy y&amp;rsquo;all!
Since you have already read señor Shackelfords blog post on setting up Endpoint Analytics Proactive remediations, we can skip the intro and dive right in.
In this blog post we will be get familiar with a somewhat novel idea that proactive remediation&amp;rsquo;s can be used for. Which, as the title of this post suggests, is the creation of a dynamic email signature in the form of a .html file using Microsoft Graph.</description></item><item><title>Intune/Autopilot Proactive Remediation</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/07/07/intune-autopilot-proactive-remediation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 16:24:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/07/07/intune-autopilot-proactive-remediation/</guid><description>What is Proactive Remediation? Proactive remediations are a pair of scripts used to detect and remediate a problem on a machine. The first script runs a query on your endpoints that returns an exit code of success or failure. We call this first script the detection script. On a successful exit code it is reported as &amp;ldquo;Without issue&amp;rdquo; in the Intune portal and nothing else is executed. On a failed exit code the second script is run which is called a remediation script.</description></item></channel></rss>