<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Graph on Systems Management Squad</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/categories/graph/</link><description>Recent content in Graph on Systems Management Squad</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sysmansquad.com/categories/graph/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Using PowerShell and Graph to update Azure AD user photos in bulk</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/12/03/2021-12-03-using-powershell-and-graph-to-update-azure-ad-user-photos-in-bulk/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/12/03/2021-12-03-using-powershell-and-graph-to-update-azure-ad-user-photos-in-bulk/</guid><description>Introduction In this post, I’ll give you some background information and show you how to utilize the Microsoft Graph API to bulk update Azure AD user photos. If you’d like to skip the background information and get straight to the nitty-gritty, click here.
Background I work at a private K-12 school in the United States. Like many schools out there, we have scheduled portraits once a year for students and staff.</description></item><item><title>Automating Outside of Business Hours Responses</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/12/30/automating-changing-out-of-business-hours-responses/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 19:20:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/12/30/automating-changing-out-of-business-hours-responses/</guid><description>Have you ever had customers emailing in outside of hours? In this post we will setup some scripted automatic maintenance of Auto-Reply responses on a user account.
We considered several possibilities but the customer did not have an Azure Subscription yet, we ended up using PowerShell, Microsoft Graph, App Authentication, and a Scheduled Task.
Our customer will be moving to Azure later so we will probably revisit this as Azure Functions, or possibly Power Automate later on.</description></item><item><title>Bulk Updating Autopilot enrolled devices with Graph API and assigning a Group Tag based on Purchase OrderID</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/08/24/bulk-updating-autopilot-enrolled-devices-with-graph-api-and-assigning-a-group-tag-based-on-purchase-orderid/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 14:31:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/08/24/bulk-updating-autopilot-enrolled-devices-with-graph-api-and-assigning-a-group-tag-based-on-purchase-orderid/</guid><description>The Problem For any new machines ordered from a vendor such as Dell that get enrolled into Autopilot you get the basic device info enrolled but nothing defining that would let it get auto-enrolled into a dynamic group easily. Purchase Order ID is included in every order we receive from Dell however I don&amp;rsquo;t want to have to add that Purchase Order ID into the dynamic device query every time a new machine gets added.</description></item></channel></rss>