<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Networking on Systems Management Squad</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/categories/networking/</link><description>Recent content in Networking on Systems Management Squad</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 14:46:22 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sysmansquad.com/categories/networking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Creating an Ubuntu 20.04 cloud template &amp; cloud-init configuration in Xen Orchestra</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/07/07/creating-an-ubuntu-20-04-cloud-template-cloud-init-configuration-in-xen-orchestra/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 14:46:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/07/07/creating-an-ubuntu-20-04-cloud-template-cloud-init-configuration-in-xen-orchestra/</guid><description>I had a need in my home lab to quickly deploy a bunch of thin clones of Ubuntu&amp;rsquo;s cloud image. I chose to use the cloud images Ubuntu provides instead of building a custom template.
Xen Orchestra has had support for cloud-init since 2015.
Quick Walkthrough Here is the short version of how this works:
Download the current 20.04 ubuntu cloud image OVA file, there should only be 1 on each build&amp;rsquo;s page.</description></item><item><title>Working around NPS limitations for AADJ Windows devices</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/04/27/working-around-nps-limitations-for-aadj-windows-devices/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 03:10:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/04/27/working-around-nps-limitations-for-aadj-windows-devices/</guid><description>⚠️ UPDATE (2023-03-11) ⚠️ Due to changes introduced by Microsoft in KB5014754 and being enforced on November 14, 2023, the name mapping method used in the scripts below will no longer work, and authentication will fail at that time. Thankfully, commenter Anders Hannus has pointed out a policy module named TameMyCerts for Microsoft Active Directory Certificate Services (AD CS). This policy module, used in conjunction with the below scripts, will let us work around Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s changes and give us the added benefit of no longer needing name mappings that are insecure.</description></item><item><title>NET-102: Build your lab</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/01/23/net-102-build-your-lab/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2020 07:13:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/01/23/net-102-build-your-lab/</guid><description>Welcome back! We&amp;rsquo;re now going to move on to the actual effort it takes to build your lab. As you recall we got pretty far last time in documenting the beginnings of our network. For this lab I&amp;rsquo;ll be using VMWare Workstation, but you can accomplish this with Microsoft Hyper-V, Oracle VirtualBox, the free tier of VMWare&amp;rsquo;s ESX, or XCP-NG.
If you haven&amp;rsquo;t read the previous post, please have a look here as each post builds upon the last.</description></item><item><title>NET-101 : Create a Basic Lab Network – Design</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2019/12/17/net-101-create-a-basic-lab-network-design/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2019 06:59:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2019/12/17/net-101-create-a-basic-lab-network-design/</guid><description>As I go through my career, I often find that the answers I take for granted are not easy to find for people who are just starting out. I had the advantage of a dedicated class on network administration to build on, but not everyone had that opportunity. While this article focuses on a lab environment, most of the content will be applicable to real life as well.
I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to include as many reference links as possible to help you learn about the concepts involved, but I cannot explain everything in one article.</description></item></channel></rss>