<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Windows on Systems Management Squad</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/categories/windows/</link><description>Recent content in Windows on Systems Management Squad</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 05:24:25 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sysmansquad.com/categories/windows/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Setting Environmental Variables with Intune and proactive remediations</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/07/02/setting-environmental-variables-with-intune-and-proactive-remediations/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 05:24:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/07/02/setting-environmental-variables-with-intune-and-proactive-remediations/</guid><description>As you may have noticed by now, there doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to be any nice built in way to set environmental variables in intune 🙁
The Problem Setting a user environmental variable using powershell is an easy task to accomplish, you basically just run the following:
1 Set-ItemProperty -Path HKCU:\Environment -Name temp -Value &amp;#34;c:\temp\&amp;#34; This works just fine, but won&amp;rsquo;t take effect until the user either reboots or signs into the device again.</description></item><item><title>Setting A Default Outlook Signature in Outlook using Intune Proactive Remediations</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/06/18/setting-a-default-outlook-signature-in-outlook-using-intune-proactive-remediations/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 12:37:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/06/18/setting-a-default-outlook-signature-in-outlook-using-intune-proactive-remediations/</guid><description>So you have already figured out how to dynamically generated outlook signatures, but now you want to make sure that people actually use them. but without preventing the use of other signatures your users might have.
Well it just so happens that I have a solution for you!
No default signature has been set
To do all this, we create a new Proactive Remediation in Intune.
Add the detection and remediations scripts from below, and set it to run as the user.</description></item><item><title>Multilingual Windows 10 20H2 OSD with ConfigMgr</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/02/16/multilingual-windows-10-20h2-osd-with-configmgr/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 10:06:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/02/16/multilingual-windows-10-20h2-osd-with-configmgr/</guid><description>Introduction In this post I&amp;rsquo;m going to share with you a task sequence for ConfigMgr / SCCM / MEMCM / MECM / MCM (this is just getting silly now) that localises Windows 10 to a language other than the default language of the OS install media.
This is a follow up from my previous post Language Packs, Language Experience Packs, Language Interface Packs… what?!
In that post I broke down the necessary bits in order to understand how to localise a Windows system.</description></item><item><title>Collecting Logs with Log Analytics for Intune devices</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/01/18/collecting-logs-with-log-analytics-for-intune-devices/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 17:38:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/01/18/collecting-logs-with-log-analytics-for-intune-devices/</guid><description>Why do I need logs? The purpose of this guide is to configure the collection of Logs in an Intune environment. By default the log analytics you enable in Intune does not give you much information beyond auditing basic things. With this approach we can record any desired log for all of our machines. There is a companion video for this setup https://youtu.be/Uw3GjMnSXbI.
Enabling Log Analytics Navigate to endpoint.microsoft.com Select Reports Select Diagnostic Settings Select Add Diagnostic setting Select all options under Log Select Send to Log Analytics workspace Select a Log Analytics workspace You can archive to a storage account to keep data longer Now that we have the log analytics workspace configured we can configure the Microsoft Monitoring Agent (MMA)</description></item><item><title>Finding Azure Virtual Machines in Configuration Manager</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/01/05/finding-azure-virtual-machines-in-configuration-manager/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 05:04:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/01/05/finding-azure-virtual-machines-in-configuration-manager/</guid><description>A request came in from my System Admin group to push certain policies only to VMs hosted in Azure. Currently, they had a naming convention being used (well, supposed to be used) to simply prefix the hostname with AZ-, but they came across a couple Domain Controllers that hadn&amp;rsquo;t installed Updates in 7+ months, and of course the names didn&amp;rsquo;t follow the accepted standard.
So I started looking for ways to identify Azure devices definitively and came across this Detect Windows Azure Virtual Machine post, which led to reading the Azure Metadata Service docs, and eventually got me to turn this into a Configuration Item / Configuration Baseline and subsequent Device Collections.</description></item><item><title>Setting ACL using Intune Endpoint Analytics Proactive Remediations</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/07/27/setting-acl-using-intune-endpoint-analytics-proactive-remediations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2020 14:56:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/07/27/setting-acl-using-intune-endpoint-analytics-proactive-remediations/</guid><description>Namaste y&amp;rsquo;all! In todays Siri dictated blog post, I will show you how you can configure access control lists (ACL) for a directory using Intune Proactive remediations.
The issue I was facing was that regular users do not have modify permissions to the public desktop on their corporate devices, meaning that the user is unable to remove annoying shortcuts that would get placed there by the various apps they install. While this is hardly a high priority task to solve.</description></item><item><title>Dynamic Outlook Email Signature Using with Intune Endpoint Analytics Proactive Remediations</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/07/08/dynamic-outlook-email-signature-using-with-intune-endpoint-analytics-proactive-remediations/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 03:09:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/07/08/dynamic-outlook-email-signature-using-with-intune-endpoint-analytics-proactive-remediations/</guid><description>Howdy y&amp;rsquo;all!
Since you have already read señor Shackelfords blog post on setting up Endpoint Analytics Proactive remediations, we can skip the intro and dive right in.
In this blog post we will be get familiar with a somewhat novel idea that proactive remediation&amp;rsquo;s can be used for. Which, as the title of this post suggests, is the creation of a dynamic email signature in the form of a .html file using Microsoft Graph.</description></item><item><title>Intune/Autopilot Proactive Remediation</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/07/07/intune-autopilot-proactive-remediation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 16:24:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/07/07/intune-autopilot-proactive-remediation/</guid><description>What is Proactive Remediation? Proactive remediations are a pair of scripts used to detect and remediate a problem on a machine. The first script runs a query on your endpoints that returns an exit code of success or failure. We call this first script the detection script. On a successful exit code it is reported as &amp;ldquo;Without issue&amp;rdquo; in the Intune portal and nothing else is executed. On a failed exit code the second script is run which is called a remediation script.</description></item><item><title>ARM (Azure Resource Manager) Templating for Windows Virtual Desktop</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/05/26/arm-azure-resource-manager-templating-for-windows-virtual-desktop/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2020 12:56:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/05/26/arm-azure-resource-manager-templating-for-windows-virtual-desktop/</guid><description>Why would I use ARM templating, isn&amp;rsquo;t the default Image Gallery fine? Well first off, what is ARM Templating? According to Microsoft &amp;ldquo;You can automate deployments and use the practice of infrastructure as code. In code, you define the infrastructure that needs to be deployed. The infrastructure code becomes part of your project. Just like application code, you store the infrastructure code in a source repository and version it&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;
What does all that mean?</description></item><item><title>NET-103 : Layering in Active Directory</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/05/19/net-103-layering-in-active-directory/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/05/19/net-103-layering-in-active-directory/</guid><description>Joe Ravi / CC BY-SA https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0 In previous articles, we&amp;rsquo;ve built the basic services you need without getting too far in the weeds. Now we&amp;rsquo;re going to layer in a central identity service.
It&amp;rsquo;s also hopefully going to be a lot shorter than previous articles, though I can&amp;rsquo;t make any promises - these things tend to all start small, then balloon rapidly.
If you&amp;rsquo;re continuing from NET-102 you&amp;rsquo;ll already have the following machines:</description></item><item><title>Intune/Autopilot Setup Companion Guide Part 2 – Windows Store for Business</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/01/27/intune-autopilot-setup-companion-guide-part-2-windows-store-for-business/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2020 19:15:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/01/27/intune-autopilot-setup-companion-guide-part-2-windows-store-for-business/</guid><description>Purpose The following blog posts will be a companion guide to Steve and Adam’s Intune training videos found at Intune.Training (this covers Episode 3) and will help you get the Windows Store for Business (WSfB, also known as Microsoft Store for Business) setup in your environment. This guide assumes that you already have followed Part 1 of this series and already have a working deployment profile. By the end of this guide you will have access to the Company Portal app and other apps of your choosing.</description></item><item><title>NET-102: Build your lab</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/01/23/net-102-build-your-lab/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2020 07:13:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/01/23/net-102-build-your-lab/</guid><description>Welcome back! We&amp;rsquo;re now going to move on to the actual effort it takes to build your lab. As you recall we got pretty far last time in documenting the beginnings of our network. For this lab I&amp;rsquo;ll be using VMWare Workstation, but you can accomplish this with Microsoft Hyper-V, Oracle VirtualBox, the free tier of VMWare&amp;rsquo;s ESX, or XCP-NG.
If you haven&amp;rsquo;t read the previous post, please have a look here as each post builds upon the last.</description></item><item><title>Windows Virtual Desktop: Creation and Management</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/01/13/wvd-creation-and-management/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 06:33:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/01/13/wvd-creation-and-management/</guid><description>THIS GUIDE IS NOW OUTDATED WITH THE RELEASE OF WVD 2.0, I will create a new blog with the updated info in the future! Some of the info below is still valid! Why Windows Virtual Desktop? Windows Virtual Desktop allows you to create virtual Windows 10 machines that can be accessed from virtually anywhere. This means you can give someone a full desktop experience from virtually anywhere including android and iOS!</description></item></channel></rss>