<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>SCCM on Systems Management Squad</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/tags/sccm/</link><description>Recent content in SCCM on Systems Management Squad</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 13:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sysmansquad.com/tags/sccm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Teams Channel Notification when OSD Fails</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/04/22/teams-channel-notification-when-osd-fails/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/04/22/teams-channel-notification-when-osd-fails/</guid><description>How would you like this lovely notification appearing within MS Teams every time a build failed? Better than getting a helpdesk ticket or not finding out at all.
Well, now you can!
Removed broken screenshot - editor
Step 1 - Configure Teams You need to make sure your O365 Administrator has enabled Incoming webhooks connectors in your O365 Tenant.
Open Teams. Select a channel, or create a new channel specific for these notifications (This is best practice so normal channels are not spammed) Click the &amp;hellip; Next to the channel name and choose Connectors Removed broken screenshot - editor</description></item><item><title>Collect Client Logs – The Fast Channel Way</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/04/08/collect-client-logs-the-fast-channel-way/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/04/08/collect-client-logs-the-fast-channel-way/</guid><description>What&amp;rsquo;s New? Starting in MEMCM 2002 there is an incredible new tool in the Client Notification tool bag. Client log collection!
This is a vital addition to the console. At first glance I thought&amp;hellip;
But then the features full value was realized!
Collecting Logs Over CMG Scenario: Increasing remote workforce, no VPN, but that nifty CMG thing is in place. What does that imply? There is no SMB access to the client.</description></item><item><title>Inventory Deprovisioned Windows 10 Apps</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/03/11/inventory-deprovisioned-windows-10-apps/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2020 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/03/11/inventory-deprovisioned-windows-10-apps/</guid><description>In my previous post I&amp;rsquo;ve shown that we can revert the deprovisioning of Windows 10 apps. This is awesome news for anyone that has removed the Windows Store. I have been unable to find any other way of restoring the Windows Store once it has been deprovisioned, so this is an awesome time saver. Instead of reimaging devices that do not have the store we can simply &amp;lsquo;reprovision&amp;rsquo; the store, and perform a feature update!</description></item><item><title>Managing Multiple Office 365 Deployments with ConfigMgr</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/02/25/managing-multiple-office-365-deployments-with-configmgr/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2020 17:36:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/02/25/managing-multiple-office-365-deployments-with-configmgr/</guid><description>At the client I&amp;rsquo;m currently working for, we have FIVE different deployments of Office 365 Client within Microsoft Enterprise Configuration Manager. The business decided that they only wanted users to have exactly what was needed. Essentially, this is the legacy approach to Office deployment in the MSI days where you could fully customise which components were installed and was easy to add bits back in at a later date.
These are the options they wanted:</description></item><item><title>Reprovision Windows 10 Apps… Wait, What?</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/01/06/reprovision-windows-10-apps-wait-what/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2020 13:54:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/01/06/reprovision-windows-10-apps-wait-what/</guid><description>Remember when we all complained that Microsoft &amp;ldquo;wasn&amp;rsquo;t respecting our app removals!&amp;rdquo; and they were all reinstalled during every feature update? Pepperidge farm remembers. Well, Microsoft was kind enough to hear our collective complaints, and take action on them. That is an awesome quality that we are seeing from the product teams at Microsoft.
Starting in Windows 10 1803, deprovisioned apps will NOT be reinstalled during a feature update. No more Solitaire returning from the dead every time we try to &amp;ldquo;Get current and stay current.</description></item></channel></rss>