<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Task Sequence on Systems Management Squad</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/categories/task-sequence/</link><description>Recent content in Task Sequence on Systems Management Squad</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 03:04:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sysmansquad.com/categories/task-sequence/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Updated Modern Driver/BIOS Management with CMG Support</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/04/27/updated-modern-driver-bios-management-with-cmg-support/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 03:04:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/04/27/updated-modern-driver-bios-management-with-cmg-support/</guid><description>Hello,
This is a long and overdue update on a solution I started working on last year to allow my organization to use the modern driver management solution without the need of the custom webservice. I also wanted the solution to use the built-in task sequence steps as much as possible to allow other administrators to customize the solution to their need without the need to go modify a big PowerShell script.</description></item><item><title>Multilingual Windows 10 20H2 OSD with ConfigMgr</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/02/16/multilingual-windows-10-20h2-osd-with-configmgr/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 10:06:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/02/16/multilingual-windows-10-20h2-osd-with-configmgr/</guid><description>Introduction In this post I&amp;rsquo;m going to share with you a task sequence for ConfigMgr / SCCM / MEMCM / MECM / MCM (this is just getting silly now) that localises Windows 10 to a language other than the default language of the OS install media.
This is a follow up from my previous post Language Packs, Language Experience Packs, Language Interface Packs… what?!
In that post I broke down the necessary bits in order to understand how to localise a Windows system.</description></item><item><title>Use the Task Sequence deployment type to deploy an application with sensitive information</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/09/27/use-the-task-sequence-deployment-type-to-deploy-an-application-with-sensitive-information/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2020 10:40:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/09/27/use-the-task-sequence-deployment-type-to-deploy-an-application-with-sensitive-information/</guid><description>Introduction Introduced with ConfigMgr 2002, the &amp;ldquo;Task Sequence as an application deployment type&amp;rdquo; feature is available in pre-release. That means it is still in active development and can contains bugs. Using a Task Sequence (TS) as a deployment type allows for more complex installation process that can even contains reboot. And as it is a Task Sequence, you can also benefit from many other feature like the use of TS variables.</description></item><item><title>Language Packs, Language Experience Packs, Language Interface Packs… what?!</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/06/08/language-packs-language-experience-packs-language-interface-packs-what/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/06/08/language-packs-language-experience-packs-language-interface-packs-what/</guid><description>For a while I have been curious on how to do Windows OSD with multiple languages &amp;ldquo;the proper way&amp;rdquo; using Configuration Manager. Whenever I have approached the subject I have always felt overwhelmed.
Googling the topic is just a hot mess. You&amp;rsquo;re faced with information that&amp;rsquo;s old, lacking real detail or generally misunderstood. My aim here is to demystify the topic and show you a solid way to do Windows 10 multi language OSD with ConfigMgr along with sound reasoning.</description></item><item><title>Modern Driver Management with the Administration Service</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/05/15/modern-driver-management-with-the-administration-service/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 14:39:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/05/15/modern-driver-management-with-the-administration-service/</guid><description>2021-04-27 update: The solution now works over CMG. Please see this post for details.
Hello!
Today I’d like to share with you a new solution I’ve developed to allow me to use the free Modern Driver Management solution from the team at MSEndpointMgr at my work. My goal is to use the process developed by them for managing drivers in a task sequence and convert it to use the ConfigMgr Administration Service since my company won&amp;rsquo;t allow me to install their third-party web service.</description></item></channel></rss>