<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>PowerShell Module on Systems Management Squad</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/tags/powershell-module/</link><description>Recent content in PowerShell Module on Systems Management Squad</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 May 2021 03:21:09 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sysmansquad.com/tags/powershell-module/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Where is the report’s data??</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/05/15/where-is-the-reports-data/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 May 2021 03:21:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/05/15/where-is-the-reports-data/</guid><description>Have you ever looked at a report on a Portal Page and wanted to know just WHERE the data just came from?
Well you can - and finding the information can be so easy. Read on below to see how.
Introduction Take for example this report on a Proactive Remediation. I used one of the built in Proactive Remediations for the example, but it could easily be one of our other Proactive Remediation posts, like Dynamic Outlook Signatures, Building VPN Connections, or Repairing Folder permissions.</description></item><item><title>Manage Distribution Point Content Using PSCMContentMgmt</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/09/04/manage-distribution-point-content-using-pscmcontentmgmt/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2020 21:59:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/09/04/manage-distribution-point-content-using-pscmcontentmgmt/</guid><description>Introduction I recently wrote PSCMContentMgmt which provides a simple and effective workflow for managing your MEMCM distribution points. Here are some of the things you can do with it:
Query content objects which are distributed to distribution point(s) or distribution point group(s) Compare content objects distributed to distribution point(s) or distribution point group(s) Find content objects in a &amp;ldquo;distribution failed&amp;rdquo; state for all or selective distribution points Remove, distribute or redistribute content objects returned by any function to distribution point(s) Find an object in your site by searching on any arbitrary ID (useful when reading logs and want to know what object an ID resolves to) Migrate a distribution point&amp;rsquo;s content to a new/different distribution point by exporting its content library to prestaged .</description></item></channel></rss>