<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Windows 10 on Systems Management Squad</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/tags/windows-10/</link><description>Recent content in Windows 10 on Systems Management Squad</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 17:22:10 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sysmansquad.com/tags/windows-10/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Signing and Deploying Applications via MSIX with Intune</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/09/15/signing-and-deploying-applications-via-msix-with-intune/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 17:22:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/09/15/signing-and-deploying-applications-via-msix-with-intune/</guid><description>Why would I want to use MSIX and what is it? MSIX is a Windows app package format that provides a modern packaging experience to all Windows apps. The MSIX package format preserves the functionality of existing app packages and/or install files in addition to enabling new, modern packaging and deployment features to Win32, WPF, and Windows Forms apps.
Do you have a bloated application? Maybe one or two that are so old it doesn&amp;rsquo;t even have any install parameters?</description></item><item><title>Inventory Deprovisioned Windows 10 Apps</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/03/11/inventory-deprovisioned-windows-10-apps/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2020 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/03/11/inventory-deprovisioned-windows-10-apps/</guid><description>In my previous post I&amp;rsquo;ve shown that we can revert the deprovisioning of Windows 10 apps. This is awesome news for anyone that has removed the Windows Store. I have been unable to find any other way of restoring the Windows Store once it has been deprovisioned, so this is an awesome time saver. Instead of reimaging devices that do not have the store we can simply &amp;lsquo;reprovision&amp;rsquo; the store, and perform a feature update!</description></item><item><title>Reprovision Windows 10 Apps… Wait, What?</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/01/06/reprovision-windows-10-apps-wait-what/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2020 13:54:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/01/06/reprovision-windows-10-apps-wait-what/</guid><description>Remember when we all complained that Microsoft &amp;ldquo;wasn&amp;rsquo;t respecting our app removals!&amp;rdquo; and they were all reinstalled during every feature update? Pepperidge farm remembers. Well, Microsoft was kind enough to hear our collective complaints, and take action on them. That is an awesome quality that we are seeing from the product teams at Microsoft.
Starting in Windows 10 1803, deprovisioned apps will NOT be reinstalled during a feature update. No more Solitaire returning from the dead every time we try to &amp;ldquo;Get current and stay current.</description></item></channel></rss>