<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Modern Device Management on Systems Management Squad</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/tags/modern-device-management/</link><description>Recent content in Modern Device Management on Systems Management Squad</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2023 00:14:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sysmansquad.com/tags/modern-device-management/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Intune Apps, Double It and Give It to The Next Admin.</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2023/04/12/intune-apps-doubleit/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2023 00:14:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2023/04/12/intune-apps-doubleit/</guid><description>Intune is a really great software management system, but there are a few issues caused by a lack of flexibility that can give you some headaches if your just starting your Intune journey. Today I am going to be highlighting an issue with targeting application updates and how we can work around it.
The Problem Defined You have an application assigned to users as an available app. That means it shows up in the company portal for self service.</description></item><item><title>Dealing With Frontline Workers and OneDrive</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2023/04/11/Dealing-With-Frontline-Workers-OneDrive/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 00:14:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2023/04/11/Dealing-With-Frontline-Workers-OneDrive/</guid><description>OneDrive is an amazing product. It allows you to separate what&amp;rsquo;s important, the data, from the tools used to transform the data,the computer. Your CEOs laptop got dropped in a bathtub? No Problem. Hand them a laptop with Intune &amp;amp; Autopilot and they&amp;rsquo;ll be back up and running within an hour or so WITH all of their files. Despite it&amp;rsquo;s integral part to modern device management it has a few quirks that can make it a difficult product to administrate at times.</description></item></channel></rss>