<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Proactive Remediations on Systems Management Squad</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/tags/proactive-remediations/</link><description>Recent content in Proactive Remediations on Systems Management Squad</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Oct 2021 13:59:21 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sysmansquad.com/tags/proactive-remediations/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Removing The Built-in Teams App in Windows 11 with Intune</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/10/08/removing-the-built-in-teams-app-in-windows-11-with-intune/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Oct 2021 13:59:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/10/08/removing-the-built-in-teams-app-in-windows-11-with-intune/</guid><description>Intro So you&amp;rsquo;ve started rolling out Windows 11 to your endpoints, and your users got confused and upset over the consumer teams apps that is installed? Understandably you wish to do something about this.
(╯°□°）╯︵ ┻━┻ No worries mate, Intune Proactive Remediations to the rescue!
The Solution The code below fixes two things.
It removes the chat by writing the registry key that disables it
the TaskbarMn DWORD controls this Then it simply uninstalls the appx package for the consumer teams app, note that this has no effect on the regular teams app.</description></item><item><title>Where is the report’s data??</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/05/15/where-is-the-reports-data/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 May 2021 03:21:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/05/15/where-is-the-reports-data/</guid><description>Have you ever looked at a report on a Portal Page and wanted to know just WHERE the data just came from?
Well you can - and finding the information can be so easy. Read on below to see how.
Introduction Take for example this report on a Proactive Remediation. I used one of the built in Proactive Remediations for the example, but it could easily be one of our other Proactive Remediation posts, like Dynamic Outlook Signatures, Building VPN Connections, or Repairing Folder permissions.</description></item><item><title>Intune/Autopilot Proactive Remediation</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/07/07/intune-autopilot-proactive-remediation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 16:24:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/07/07/intune-autopilot-proactive-remediation/</guid><description>What is Proactive Remediation? Proactive remediations are a pair of scripts used to detect and remediate a problem on a machine. The first script runs a query on your endpoints that returns an exit code of success or failure. We call this first script the detection script. On a successful exit code it is reported as &amp;ldquo;Without issue&amp;rdquo; in the Intune portal and nothing else is executed. On a failed exit code the second script is run which is called a remediation script.</description></item></channel></rss>