<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Office on Systems Management Squad</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/categories/office/</link><description>Recent content in Office on Systems Management Squad</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 03:09:31 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sysmansquad.com/categories/office/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Dynamic Outlook Email Signature Using with Intune Endpoint Analytics Proactive Remediations</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/07/08/dynamic-outlook-email-signature-using-with-intune-endpoint-analytics-proactive-remediations/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 03:09:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/07/08/dynamic-outlook-email-signature-using-with-intune-endpoint-analytics-proactive-remediations/</guid><description>Howdy y&amp;rsquo;all!
Since you have already read señor Shackelfords blog post on setting up Endpoint Analytics Proactive remediations, we can skip the intro and dive right in.
In this blog post we will be get familiar with a somewhat novel idea that proactive remediation&amp;rsquo;s can be used for. Which, as the title of this post suggests, is the creation of a dynamic email signature in the form of a .html file using Microsoft Graph.</description></item><item><title>Teams Channel Notification when OSD Fails</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/04/22/teams-channel-notification-when-osd-fails/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/04/22/teams-channel-notification-when-osd-fails/</guid><description>How would you like this lovely notification appearing within MS Teams every time a build failed? Better than getting a helpdesk ticket or not finding out at all.
Well, now you can!
Removed broken screenshot - editor
Step 1 - Configure Teams You need to make sure your O365 Administrator has enabled Incoming webhooks connectors in your O365 Tenant.
Open Teams. Select a channel, or create a new channel specific for these notifications (This is best practice so normal channels are not spammed) Click the &amp;hellip; Next to the channel name and choose Connectors Removed broken screenshot - editor</description></item><item><title>Managing Multiple Office 365 Deployments with ConfigMgr</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/02/25/managing-multiple-office-365-deployments-with-configmgr/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2020 17:36:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/02/25/managing-multiple-office-365-deployments-with-configmgr/</guid><description>At the client I&amp;rsquo;m currently working for, we have FIVE different deployments of Office 365 Client within Microsoft Enterprise Configuration Manager. The business decided that they only wanted users to have exactly what was needed. Essentially, this is the legacy approach to Office deployment in the MSI days where you could fully customise which components were installed and was easy to add bits back in at a later date.
These are the options they wanted:</description></item></channel></rss>