<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>General on Systems Management Squad</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/categories/general/</link><description>Recent content in General on Systems Management Squad</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 May 2021 03:21:09 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sysmansquad.com/categories/general/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Where is the report’s data??</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/05/15/where-is-the-reports-data/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 May 2021 03:21:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/05/15/where-is-the-reports-data/</guid><description>Have you ever looked at a report on a Portal Page and wanted to know just WHERE the data just came from?
Well you can - and finding the information can be so easy. Read on below to see how.
Introduction Take for example this report on a Proactive Remediation. I used one of the built in Proactive Remediations for the example, but it could easily be one of our other Proactive Remediation posts, like Dynamic Outlook Signatures, Building VPN Connections, or Repairing Folder permissions.</description></item><item><title>Create a small discord.py bot to deploy a server</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/02/13/create-a-small-discord-py-bot-to-deploy-a-server/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2021 04:10:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/02/13/create-a-small-discord-py-bot-to-deploy-a-server/</guid><description>I volunteer to help run Southwest CCDC every year, and had a need to deploy all of the communication infrastructure in a hurry. With Covid Times™ upon us, we needed to move a competition that usually has at least one round in person to all-virtual. Discord was the obvious choice for how to do that successfully - it is targeted to communities of people, and has moderation tools. My discord server needed to have a few things:</description></item><item><title>Access Public GitHub Repo Feeds in Power Automate</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/02/09/access-public-github-repo-feeds-in-power-automate/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2021 13:26:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/02/09/access-public-github-repo-feeds-in-power-automate/</guid><description>Have you ever wanted to get a simple notification when there is a new Release for your favorite PowerShell Module or other Public Repo on GitHub? In this post we&amp;rsquo;ll talk about how you can use Power Automate to watch for new releases and trigger events on these and send out Teams messages, Emails, or even Kick off an Azure Function or similar automation.
Introduction In my previous post, we did some automation with client-side scripts and Microsoft Graph to update Outlook Auto-Responses on a schedule.</description></item><item><title>Collecting Logs with Log Analytics for Intune devices</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/01/18/collecting-logs-with-log-analytics-for-intune-devices/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 17:38:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/01/18/collecting-logs-with-log-analytics-for-intune-devices/</guid><description>Why do I need logs? The purpose of this guide is to configure the collection of Logs in an Intune environment. By default the log analytics you enable in Intune does not give you much information beyond auditing basic things. With this approach we can record any desired log for all of our machines. There is a companion video for this setup https://youtu.be/Uw3GjMnSXbI.
Enabling Log Analytics Navigate to endpoint.microsoft.com Select Reports Select Diagnostic Settings Select Add Diagnostic setting Select all options under Log Select Send to Log Analytics workspace Select a Log Analytics workspace You can archive to a storage account to keep data longer Now that we have the log analytics workspace configured we can configure the Microsoft Monitoring Agent (MMA)</description></item><item><title>Every day tools for the productive IT professional</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/10/05/every-day-tools-for-the-productive-it-professional/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2020 16:11:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/10/05/every-day-tools-for-the-productive-it-professional/</guid><description>In this post I want to share with you a list of tips and tools that I feel have boosted my day-to-day productivity on the computer.
The title suggests this is only for IT professionals. However I can&amp;rsquo;t see why power users can&amp;rsquo;t appreciate what&amp;rsquo;s here too.
You may already have different tools that achieve similar, or better, functionality, so drop a comment below or tweet your tip on Twitter using the hashtag #EveryDayITPro.</description></item></channel></rss>