<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Documentation on Systems Management Squad</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/categories/documentation/</link><description>Recent content in Documentation on Systems Management Squad</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 14:46:22 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sysmansquad.com/categories/documentation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Creating an Ubuntu 20.04 cloud template &amp; cloud-init configuration in Xen Orchestra</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/07/07/creating-an-ubuntu-20-04-cloud-template-cloud-init-configuration-in-xen-orchestra/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 14:46:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/07/07/creating-an-ubuntu-20-04-cloud-template-cloud-init-configuration-in-xen-orchestra/</guid><description>I had a need in my home lab to quickly deploy a bunch of thin clones of Ubuntu&amp;rsquo;s cloud image. I chose to use the cloud images Ubuntu provides instead of building a custom template.
Xen Orchestra has had support for cloud-init since 2015.
Quick Walkthrough Here is the short version of how this works:
Download the current 20.04 ubuntu cloud image OVA file, there should only be 1 on each build&amp;rsquo;s page.</description></item><item><title>Where is the report’s data??</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/05/15/where-is-the-reports-data/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 May 2021 03:21:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/05/15/where-is-the-reports-data/</guid><description>Have you ever looked at a report on a Portal Page and wanted to know just WHERE the data just came from?
Well you can - and finding the information can be so easy. Read on below to see how.
Introduction Take for example this report on a Proactive Remediation. I used one of the built in Proactive Remediations for the example, but it could easily be one of our other Proactive Remediation posts, like Dynamic Outlook Signatures, Building VPN Connections, or Repairing Folder permissions.</description></item><item><title>Access Public GitHub Repo Feeds in Power Automate</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/02/09/access-public-github-repo-feeds-in-power-automate/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2021 13:26:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/02/09/access-public-github-repo-feeds-in-power-automate/</guid><description>Have you ever wanted to get a simple notification when there is a new Release for your favorite PowerShell Module or other Public Repo on GitHub? In this post we&amp;rsquo;ll talk about how you can use Power Automate to watch for new releases and trigger events on these and send out Teams messages, Emails, or even Kick off an Azure Function or similar automation.
Introduction In my previous post, we did some automation with client-side scripts and Microsoft Graph to update Outlook Auto-Responses on a schedule.</description></item><item><title>Collecting Logs with Log Analytics for Intune devices</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/01/18/collecting-logs-with-log-analytics-for-intune-devices/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 17:38:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/01/18/collecting-logs-with-log-analytics-for-intune-devices/</guid><description>Why do I need logs? The purpose of this guide is to configure the collection of Logs in an Intune environment. By default the log analytics you enable in Intune does not give you much information beyond auditing basic things. With this approach we can record any desired log for all of our machines. There is a companion video for this setup https://youtu.be/Uw3GjMnSXbI.
Enabling Log Analytics Navigate to endpoint.microsoft.com Select Reports Select Diagnostic Settings Select Add Diagnostic setting Select all options under Log Select Send to Log Analytics workspace Select a Log Analytics workspace You can archive to a storage account to keep data longer Now that we have the log analytics workspace configured we can configure the Microsoft Monitoring Agent (MMA)</description></item><item><title>Dynamic Outlook Email Signature Using with Intune Endpoint Analytics Proactive Remediations</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/07/08/dynamic-outlook-email-signature-using-with-intune-endpoint-analytics-proactive-remediations/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 03:09:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/07/08/dynamic-outlook-email-signature-using-with-intune-endpoint-analytics-proactive-remediations/</guid><description>Howdy y&amp;rsquo;all!
Since you have already read señor Shackelfords blog post on setting up Endpoint Analytics Proactive remediations, we can skip the intro and dive right in.
In this blog post we will be get familiar with a somewhat novel idea that proactive remediation&amp;rsquo;s can be used for. Which, as the title of this post suggests, is the creation of a dynamic email signature in the form of a .html file using Microsoft Graph.</description></item><item><title>Intune/Autopilot Proactive Remediation</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/07/07/intune-autopilot-proactive-remediation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 16:24:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/07/07/intune-autopilot-proactive-remediation/</guid><description>What is Proactive Remediation? Proactive remediations are a pair of scripts used to detect and remediate a problem on a machine. The first script runs a query on your endpoints that returns an exit code of success or failure. We call this first script the detection script. On a successful exit code it is reported as &amp;ldquo;Without issue&amp;rdquo; in the Intune portal and nothing else is executed. On a failed exit code the second script is run which is called a remediation script.</description></item><item><title>Sharing Google Meet Links With Students Safely Can Be Confusing For I.T. Pros, Let Alone Teachers</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/04/26/sharing-google-meet-links-with-students-safely/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 20:26:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/04/26/sharing-google-meet-links-with-students-safely/</guid><description>TL;DR: Classroom-Meet integrated meeting links are safe. Nickname Meet meeting links are safe. Blank/Non-Nickname Meet meeting links ARE NOT safe. Calendar generated Meet meeting links ARE NOT safe. I&amp;rsquo;ll start by saying that I recognize COVID-19 and it&amp;rsquo;s impact on technology use in K-12 public education put many of us in a position of building the airplane as we&amp;rsquo;re flying on it. Administration, Curriculum and Technology have been working hard in school districts around the world to quickly train and support staff and faculty using systems they may never have heard of before this situation.</description></item><item><title>To Trust Or Not To Trust (UNSIGNED DRIVERS): That Is The Question</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/02/04/to-trust-or-not-to-trust-unsigned-drivers-that-is-the-question/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 06:48:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/02/04/to-trust-or-not-to-trust-unsigned-drivers-that-is-the-question/</guid><description>This post is intended to help others who might want to better understand why their Operating System Deployment (OSD) task sequence (TS) is failing during the Setup Windows and Configuration Manager step with an error code of 0x80004005 and how to identify the unsigned drivers in your driver package that might be causing it. Maybe my google-fu was failing me, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t see anything else out there that was a guided tour with pictures through the old Microsoft article on this issue.</description></item><item><title>Intune/Autopilot Setup Companion Guide Part 2 – Windows Store for Business</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/01/27/intune-autopilot-setup-companion-guide-part-2-windows-store-for-business/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2020 19:15:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/01/27/intune-autopilot-setup-companion-guide-part-2-windows-store-for-business/</guid><description>Purpose The following blog posts will be a companion guide to Steve and Adam’s Intune training videos found at Intune.Training (this covers Episode 3) and will help you get the Windows Store for Business (WSfB, also known as Microsoft Store for Business) setup in your environment. This guide assumes that you already have followed Part 1 of this series and already have a working deployment profile. By the end of this guide you will have access to the Company Portal app and other apps of your choosing.</description></item><item><title>NET-101 : Create a Basic Lab Network – Design</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2019/12/17/net-101-create-a-basic-lab-network-design/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2019 06:59:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2019/12/17/net-101-create-a-basic-lab-network-design/</guid><description>As I go through my career, I often find that the answers I take for granted are not easy to find for people who are just starting out. I had the advantage of a dedicated class on network administration to build on, but not everyone had that opportunity. While this article focuses on a lab environment, most of the content will be applicable to real life as well.
I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to include as many reference links as possible to help you learn about the concepts involved, but I cannot explain everything in one article.</description></item></channel></rss>