<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Systems Management Squad</title><link>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Systems Management Squad</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 15:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.sysmansquad.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Deploy languages via Software Center with PSCMWin10Language</title><link>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2020/06/08/deploy-languages-via-software-center-with-pscmwin10language/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2020/06/08/deploy-languages-via-software-center-with-pscmwin10language/</guid><description>This post complements my other post, where I walk-through the differences of LP, LIP, LXP and FoD.
Here I will show you how to use a PowerShell module I wrote, PSCMWin10Languages, to create Microsoft Endpoint Manager Configuration Manager Applications for each language you want to deploy via the Software Center.
These Applications are not for OSD. It changes the language only for the user who installs the Application via the Software Center.</description></item><item><title>Language Packs, Language Experience Packs, Language Interface Packs… what?!</title><link>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2020/06/08/language-packs-language-experience-packs-language-interface-packs-what/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2020/06/08/language-packs-language-experience-packs-language-interface-packs-what/</guid><description>For a while I have been curious on how to do Windows OSD with multiple languages &amp;ldquo;the proper way&amp;rdquo; using Configuration Manager. Whenever I have approached the subject I have always felt overwhelmed.
Googling the topic is just a hot mess. You&amp;rsquo;re faced with information that&amp;rsquo;s old, lacking real detail or generally misunderstood. My aim here is to demystify the topic and show you a solid way to do Windows 10 multi language OSD with ConfigMgr along with sound reasoning.</description></item><item><title>ARM (Azure Resource Manager) Templating for Windows Virtual Desktop</title><link>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2020/05/26/arm-azure-resource-manager-templating-for-windows-virtual-desktop/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2020 12:56:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2020/05/26/arm-azure-resource-manager-templating-for-windows-virtual-desktop/</guid><description>Why would I use ARM templating, isn&amp;rsquo;t the default Image Gallery fine? Well first off, what is ARM Templating? According to Microsoft &amp;ldquo;You can automate deployments and use the practice of infrastructure as code. In code, you define the infrastructure that needs to be deployed. The infrastructure code becomes part of your project. Just like application code, you store the infrastructure code in a source repository and version it&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;
What does all that mean?</description></item><item><title>NET-103 : Layering in Active Directory</title><link>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2020/05/19/net-103-layering-in-active-directory/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2020/05/19/net-103-layering-in-active-directory/</guid><description>Joe Ravi / CC BY-SA https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0
In previous articles, we&amp;rsquo;ve built the basic services you need without getting too far in the weeds. Now we&amp;rsquo;re going to layer in a central identity service.
It&amp;rsquo;s also hopefully going to be a lot shorter than previous articles, though I can&amp;rsquo;t make any promises - these things tend to all start small, then balloon rapidly.
If you&amp;rsquo;re continuing from NET-102 you&amp;rsquo;ll already have the following machines:</description></item><item><title>Modern Driver Management with the Administration Service</title><link>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2020/05/15/modern-driver-management-with-the-administration-service/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 14:39:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2020/05/15/modern-driver-management-with-the-administration-service/</guid><description>2021-04-27 update: The solution now works over CMG. Please see this post for details.
Hello!
Today I’d like to share with you a new solution I’ve developed to allow me to use the free Modern Driver Management solution from the team at MSEndpointMgr at my work. My goal is to use the process developed by them for managing drivers in a task sequence and convert it to use the ConfigMgr Administration Service since my company won&amp;rsquo;t allow me to install their third-party web service.</description></item><item><title>Sharing Google Meet Links With Students Safely Can Be Confusing For I.T. Pros, Let Alone Teachers</title><link>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2020/04/26/sharing-google-meet-links-with-students-safely/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 20:26:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2020/04/26/sharing-google-meet-links-with-students-safely/</guid><description>TL;DR: Classroom-Meet integrated meeting links are safe. Nickname Meet meeting links are safe. Blank/Non-Nickname Meet meeting links ARE NOT safe. Calendar generated Meet meeting links ARE NOT safe. I&amp;rsquo;ll start by saying that I recognize COVID-19 and it&amp;rsquo;s impact on technology use in K-12 public education put many of us in a position of building the airplane as we&amp;rsquo;re flying on it. Administration, Curriculum and Technology have been working hard in school districts around the world to quickly train and support staff and faculty using systems they may never have heard of before this situation.</description></item><item><title>Teams Channel Notification when OSD Fails</title><link>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2020/04/22/teams-channel-notification-when-osd-fails/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2020/04/22/teams-channel-notification-when-osd-fails/</guid><description>How would you like this lovely notification appearing within MS Teams every time a build failed? Better than getting a helpdesk ticket or not finding out at all.
Well, now you can!
Removed broken screenshot - editor
Step 1 - Configure Teams You need to make sure your O365 Administrator has enabled Incoming webhooks connectors in your O365 Tenant.
Open Teams. Select a channel, or create a new channel specific for these notifications (This is best practice so normal channels are not spammed) Click the &amp;hellip; Next to the channel name and choose Connectors Removed broken screenshot - editor</description></item><item><title>Collect Client Logs – The Fast Channel Way</title><link>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2020/04/08/collect-client-logs-the-fast-channel-way/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2020/04/08/collect-client-logs-the-fast-channel-way/</guid><description>What&amp;rsquo;s New? Starting in MEMCM 2002 there is an incredible new tool in the Client Notification tool bag. Client log collection!
This is a vital addition to the console. At first glance I thought&amp;hellip;
But then the features full value was realized!
Collecting Logs Over CMG Scenario: Increasing remote workforce, no VPN, but that nifty CMG thing is in place. What does that imply? There is no SMB access to the client.</description></item><item><title>Inventory Deprovisioned Windows 10 Apps</title><link>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2020/03/11/inventory-deprovisioned-windows-10-apps/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2020 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2020/03/11/inventory-deprovisioned-windows-10-apps/</guid><description>In my previous post I&amp;rsquo;ve shown that we can revert the deprovisioning of Windows 10 apps. This is awesome news for anyone that has removed the Windows Store. I have been unable to find any other way of restoring the Windows Store once it has been deprovisioned, so this is an awesome time saver. Instead of reimaging devices that do not have the store we can simply &amp;lsquo;reprovision&amp;rsquo; the store, and perform a feature update!</description></item><item><title>Managing Multiple Office 365 Deployments with ConfigMgr</title><link>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2021/02/25/managing-multiple-office-365-deployments-with-configmgr/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2020 17:36:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2021/02/25/managing-multiple-office-365-deployments-with-configmgr/</guid><description>At the client I&amp;rsquo;m currently working for, we have FIVE different deployments of Office 365 Client within Microsoft Enterprise Configuration Manager. The business decided that they only wanted users to have exactly what was needed. Essentially, this is the legacy approach to Office deployment in the MSI days where you could fully customise which components were installed and was easy to add bits back in at a later date.
These are the options they wanted:</description></item><item><title>To Trust Or Not To Trust (UNSIGNED DRIVERS): That Is The Question</title><link>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2021/02/04/to-trust-or-not-to-trust-unsigned-drivers-that-is-the-question/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 06:48:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2021/02/04/to-trust-or-not-to-trust-unsigned-drivers-that-is-the-question/</guid><description>This post is intended to help others who might want to better understand why their Operating System Deployment (OSD) task sequence (TS) is failing during the Setup Windows and Configuration Manager step with an error code of 0x80004005 and how to identify the unsigned drivers in your driver package that might be causing it. Maybe my google-fu was failing me, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t see anything else out there that was a guided tour with pictures through the old Microsoft article on this issue.</description></item><item><title>Intune/Autopilot Setup Companion Guide Part 2 – Windows Store for Business</title><link>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2021/01/27/intune-autopilot-setup-companion-guide-part-2-windows-store-for-business/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2020 19:15:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2021/01/27/intune-autopilot-setup-companion-guide-part-2-windows-store-for-business/</guid><description>Purpose The following blog posts will be a companion guide to Steve and Adam’s Intune training videos found at Intune.Training (this covers Episode 3) and will help you get the Windows Store for Business (WSfB, also known as Microsoft Store for Business) setup in your environment. This guide assumes that you already have followed Part 1 of this series and already have a working deployment profile. By the end of this guide you will have access to the Company Portal app and other apps of your choosing.</description></item><item><title>NET-102: Build your lab</title><link>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2021/01/23/net-102-build-your-lab/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2020 07:13:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2021/01/23/net-102-build-your-lab/</guid><description>Welcome back! We&amp;rsquo;re now going to move on to the actual effort it takes to build your lab. As you recall we got pretty far last time in documenting the beginnings of our network. For this lab I&amp;rsquo;ll be using VMWare Workstation, but you can accomplish this with Microsoft Hyper-V, Oracle VirtualBox, the free tier of VMWare&amp;rsquo;s ESX, or XCP-NG.
If you haven&amp;rsquo;t read the previous post, please have a look here as each post builds upon the last.</description></item><item><title>Windows Virtual Desktop: Creation and Management</title><link>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2021/01/13/wvd-creation-and-management/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 06:33:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2021/01/13/wvd-creation-and-management/</guid><description>THIS GUIDE IS NOW OUTDATED WITH THE RELEASE OF WVD 2.0, I will create a new blog with the updated info in the future! Some of the info below is still valid! Why Windows Virtual Desktop? Windows Virtual Desktop allows you to create virtual Windows 10 machines that can be accessed from virtually anywhere. This means you can give someone a full desktop experience from virtually anywhere including android and iOS!</description></item><item><title>Reprovision Windows 10 Apps… Wait, What?</title><link>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2021/01/06/reprovision-windows-10-apps-wait-what/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2020 13:54:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2021/01/06/reprovision-windows-10-apps-wait-what/</guid><description>Remember when we all complained that Microsoft &amp;ldquo;wasn&amp;rsquo;t respecting our app removals!&amp;rdquo; and they were all reinstalled during every feature update? Pepperidge farm remembers. Well, Microsoft was kind enough to hear our collective complaints, and take action on them. That is an awesome quality that we are seeing from the product teams at Microsoft.
Starting in Windows 10 1803, deprovisioned apps will NOT be reinstalled during a feature update. No more Solitaire returning from the dead every time we try to &amp;ldquo;Get current and stay current.</description></item><item><title>Intune/Autopilot Setup Companion Guide Part 1</title><link>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2019/12/18/autopilot-setup-part-1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2019 14:50:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2019/12/18/autopilot-setup-part-1/</guid><description>Purpose The following blog posts will be a companion guide to Steve and Adam&amp;rsquo;s Intune training videos found at Intune.Training (this covers Episode 1 and 2) and will help you get Autopilot going in your environment. This guide assumes that you already have office 365 and azure configured. By the end of this guide you will have a working bare bones Autopilot configuration. This has been a major request from several people in the WinAdmins community.</description></item><item><title>NET-101 : Create a Basic Lab Network – Design</title><link>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2019/12/17/net-101-create-a-basic-lab-network-design/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2019 06:59:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2019/12/17/net-101-create-a-basic-lab-network-design/</guid><description>As I go through my career, I often find that the answers I take for granted are not easy to find for people who are just starting out. I had the advantage of a dedicated class on network administration to build on, but not everyone had that opportunity. While this article focuses on a lab environment, most of the content will be applicable to real life as well.
I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to include as many reference links as possible to help you learn about the concepts involved, but I cannot explain everything in one article.</description></item><item><title>How to use modules and package providers during OSD with MECM (SCCM/MEMCM)</title><link>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2019/12/12/how-to-use-modules-and-package-providers-during-osd-with-mecm-sccm-memcm/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2019 15:53:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.sysmansquad.com/2019/12/12/how-to-use-modules-and-package-providers-during-osd-with-mecm-sccm-memcm/</guid><description>For the past few days, I&amp;rsquo;ve been implementing SnipeIT into our environment to start actually tracking assets as opposed to the archaic spreadsheet we had going. I wanted to add any new machine that were imaged into the database right away without any input from me. That way, all I had to do was assign a user to the device in the asset management portal for SnipeIT, and I was good to go.</description></item></channel></rss>