<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Azure on Systems Management Squad</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/tags/azure/</link><description>Recent content in Azure on Systems Management Squad</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 May 2021 03:21:09 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sysmansquad.com/tags/azure/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Where is the report’s data??</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/05/15/where-is-the-reports-data/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 May 2021 03:21:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/05/15/where-is-the-reports-data/</guid><description>Have you ever looked at a report on a Portal Page and wanted to know just WHERE the data just came from?
Well you can - and finding the information can be so easy. Read on below to see how.
Introduction Take for example this report on a Proactive Remediation. I used one of the built in Proactive Remediations for the example, but it could easily be one of our other Proactive Remediation posts, like Dynamic Outlook Signatures, Building VPN Connections, or Repairing Folder permissions.</description></item><item><title>Access Public GitHub Repo Feeds in Power Automate</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/02/09/access-public-github-repo-feeds-in-power-automate/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2021 13:26:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/02/09/access-public-github-repo-feeds-in-power-automate/</guid><description>Have you ever wanted to get a simple notification when there is a new Release for your favorite PowerShell Module or other Public Repo on GitHub? In this post we&amp;rsquo;ll talk about how you can use Power Automate to watch for new releases and trigger events on these and send out Teams messages, Emails, or even Kick off an Azure Function or similar automation.
Introduction In my previous post, we did some automation with client-side scripts and Microsoft Graph to update Outlook Auto-Responses on a schedule.</description></item><item><title>Find Microsoft Accounts on Company Domains</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/11/23/find-microsoft-accounts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/11/23/find-microsoft-accounts/</guid><description>The other day I was helping someone over in the WinAdmins Discord. Their users kept getting confused about what their passwords were, and it was causing a lot of HelpDesk tickets. Let&amp;rsquo;s find out what users have Microsoft accounts on the company domain so we can help move those accounts elsewhere to streamline the user experience.
Update on Prevention: Microsoft has introduced some changes that at least seem to prevent NEW Microsoft Accounts on Company Domains.</description></item></channel></rss>