<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>How-To on Systems Management Squad</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/categories/how-to/</link><description>Recent content in How-To on Systems Management Squad</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 14:46:22 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sysmansquad.com/categories/how-to/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Creating an Ubuntu 20.04 cloud template &amp; cloud-init configuration in Xen Orchestra</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/07/07/creating-an-ubuntu-20-04-cloud-template-cloud-init-configuration-in-xen-orchestra/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 14:46:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/07/07/creating-an-ubuntu-20-04-cloud-template-cloud-init-configuration-in-xen-orchestra/</guid><description>I had a need in my home lab to quickly deploy a bunch of thin clones of Ubuntu&amp;rsquo;s cloud image. I chose to use the cloud images Ubuntu provides instead of building a custom template.
Xen Orchestra has had support for cloud-init since 2015.
Quick Walkthrough Here is the short version of how this works:
Download the current 20.04 ubuntu cloud image OVA file, there should only be 1 on each build&amp;rsquo;s page.</description></item><item><title>Setting Environmental Variables with Intune and proactive remediations</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/07/02/setting-environmental-variables-with-intune-and-proactive-remediations/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 05:24:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/07/02/setting-environmental-variables-with-intune-and-proactive-remediations/</guid><description>As you may have noticed by now, there doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to be any nice built in way to set environmental variables in intune 🙁
The Problem Setting a user environmental variable using powershell is an easy task to accomplish, you basically just run the following:
1 Set-ItemProperty -Path HKCU:\Environment -Name temp -Value &amp;#34;c:\temp\&amp;#34; This works just fine, but won&amp;rsquo;t take effect until the user either reboots or signs into the device again.</description></item><item><title>Where is the report’s data??</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/05/15/where-is-the-reports-data/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 May 2021 03:21:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/05/15/where-is-the-reports-data/</guid><description>Have you ever looked at a report on a Portal Page and wanted to know just WHERE the data just came from?
Well you can - and finding the information can be so easy. Read on below to see how.
Introduction Take for example this report on a Proactive Remediation. I used one of the built in Proactive Remediations for the example, but it could easily be one of our other Proactive Remediation posts, like Dynamic Outlook Signatures, Building VPN Connections, or Repairing Folder permissions.</description></item><item><title>Create a new WinPE boot image</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/02/22/create-a-new-winpe-boot-image/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 09:51:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/02/22/create-a-new-winpe-boot-image/</guid><description>Introduction In this post I&amp;rsquo;ll show you how you can create a new boot image in ConfigMgr.
There&amp;rsquo;s plenty of good content out there already on this, but I was interested to write this because I didn&amp;rsquo;t see many PowerShell examples out there until I came across Michael Niehaus&amp;rsquo; post on Build your own Windows PE image. A fantastic post, highly recommend reading it. Michael provided a useful script at the end of this post in a .</description></item><item><title>Create a small discord.py bot to deploy a server</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/02/13/create-a-small-discord-py-bot-to-deploy-a-server/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2021 04:10:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/02/13/create-a-small-discord-py-bot-to-deploy-a-server/</guid><description>I volunteer to help run Southwest CCDC every year, and had a need to deploy all of the communication infrastructure in a hurry. With Covid Times™ upon us, we needed to move a competition that usually has at least one round in person to all-virtual. Discord was the obvious choice for how to do that successfully - it is targeted to communities of people, and has moderation tools. My discord server needed to have a few things:</description></item><item><title>Access Public GitHub Repo Feeds in Power Automate</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/02/09/access-public-github-repo-feeds-in-power-automate/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2021 13:26:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/02/09/access-public-github-repo-feeds-in-power-automate/</guid><description>Have you ever wanted to get a simple notification when there is a new Release for your favorite PowerShell Module or other Public Repo on GitHub? In this post we&amp;rsquo;ll talk about how you can use Power Automate to watch for new releases and trigger events on these and send out Teams messages, Emails, or even Kick off an Azure Function or similar automation.
Introduction In my previous post, we did some automation with client-side scripts and Microsoft Graph to update Outlook Auto-Responses on a schedule.</description></item><item><title>Collecting Logs with Log Analytics for Intune devices</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/01/18/collecting-logs-with-log-analytics-for-intune-devices/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 17:38:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/01/18/collecting-logs-with-log-analytics-for-intune-devices/</guid><description>Why do I need logs? The purpose of this guide is to configure the collection of Logs in an Intune environment. By default the log analytics you enable in Intune does not give you much information beyond auditing basic things. With this approach we can record any desired log for all of our machines. There is a companion video for this setup https://youtu.be/Uw3GjMnSXbI.
Enabling Log Analytics Navigate to endpoint.microsoft.com Select Reports Select Diagnostic Settings Select Add Diagnostic setting Select all options under Log Select Send to Log Analytics workspace Select a Log Analytics workspace You can archive to a storage account to keep data longer Now that we have the log analytics workspace configured we can configure the Microsoft Monitoring Agent (MMA)</description></item><item><title>Automating Outside of Business Hours Responses</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/12/30/automating-changing-out-of-business-hours-responses/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 19:20:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/12/30/automating-changing-out-of-business-hours-responses/</guid><description>Have you ever had customers emailing in outside of hours? In this post we will setup some scripted automatic maintenance of Auto-Reply responses on a user account.
We considered several possibilities but the customer did not have an Azure Subscription yet, we ended up using PowerShell, Microsoft Graph, App Authentication, and a Scheduled Task.
Our customer will be moving to Azure later so we will probably revisit this as Azure Functions, or possibly Power Automate later on.</description></item><item><title>Mapping Network Drives on Intune Devices</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/12/16/mapping-network-drives-on-intune-devices/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2020 19:04:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/12/16/mapping-network-drives-on-intune-devices/</guid><description>This guide is part of a video series companion guide on setting up mapped drives on Intune devices - you can watch the video here S02E18 How to Map Network Drives on Microsoft Intune Devices - (I.T)! This is rather simple but I will be adding some useful bits of code for people who do not have an always on VPN solution for all those Work From Home scenarios.
Creating the script Before we get started let me explain how this process works.</description></item><item><title>Find Microsoft Accounts on Company Domains</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/11/23/find-microsoft-accounts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/11/23/find-microsoft-accounts/</guid><description>The other day I was helping someone over in the WinAdmins Discord. Their users kept getting confused about what their passwords were, and it was causing a lot of HelpDesk tickets. Let&amp;rsquo;s find out what users have Microsoft accounts on the company domain so we can help move those accounts elsewhere to streamline the user experience.
Update on Prevention: Microsoft has introduced some changes that at least seem to prevent NEW Microsoft Accounts on Company Domains.</description></item><item><title>ConfigMgr and The Case of the Mysterious {3DA228BE-34DA-49f4-A081-66465B077429} Folder</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/09/30/configmgr-and-the-case-of-the-mysterious-3da228be-34da-49f4-a081-66465b077429-folder/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 05:50:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/09/30/configmgr-and-the-case-of-the-mysterious-3da228be-34da-49f4-a081-66465b077429-folder/</guid><description>Over the weekend I ran into a weird issue that I hadn&amp;rsquo;t seen before. I was upgrading half of the Distribution Points for a client who&amp;rsquo;s ConfigMgr was in need of some TLC. I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on getting their overall infrastructure healthy and that includes upgrading their DPs from Windows Server 2012 to Windows Server 2016 (and eventually 2019).
Once I started the upgrades I worked on other things while checking in on them periodically.</description></item><item><title>Setting ACL using Intune Endpoint Analytics Proactive Remediations</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/07/27/setting-acl-using-intune-endpoint-analytics-proactive-remediations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2020 14:56:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/07/27/setting-acl-using-intune-endpoint-analytics-proactive-remediations/</guid><description>Namaste y&amp;rsquo;all! In todays Siri dictated blog post, I will show you how you can configure access control lists (ACL) for a directory using Intune Proactive remediations.
The issue I was facing was that regular users do not have modify permissions to the public desktop on their corporate devices, meaning that the user is unable to remove annoying shortcuts that would get placed there by the various apps they install. While this is hardly a high priority task to solve.</description></item><item><title>Dynamic Outlook Email Signature Using with Intune Endpoint Analytics Proactive Remediations</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/07/08/dynamic-outlook-email-signature-using-with-intune-endpoint-analytics-proactive-remediations/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 03:09:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/07/08/dynamic-outlook-email-signature-using-with-intune-endpoint-analytics-proactive-remediations/</guid><description>Howdy y&amp;rsquo;all!
Since you have already read señor Shackelfords blog post on setting up Endpoint Analytics Proactive remediations, we can skip the intro and dive right in.
In this blog post we will be get familiar with a somewhat novel idea that proactive remediation&amp;rsquo;s can be used for. Which, as the title of this post suggests, is the creation of a dynamic email signature in the form of a .html file using Microsoft Graph.</description></item><item><title>Intune/Autopilot Proactive Remediation</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/07/07/intune-autopilot-proactive-remediation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 16:24:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/07/07/intune-autopilot-proactive-remediation/</guid><description>What is Proactive Remediation? Proactive remediations are a pair of scripts used to detect and remediate a problem on a machine. The first script runs a query on your endpoints that returns an exit code of success or failure. We call this first script the detection script. On a successful exit code it is reported as &amp;ldquo;Without issue&amp;rdquo; in the Intune portal and nothing else is executed. On a failed exit code the second script is run which is called a remediation script.</description></item><item><title>Language Packs, Language Experience Packs, Language Interface Packs… what?!</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/06/08/language-packs-language-experience-packs-language-interface-packs-what/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/06/08/language-packs-language-experience-packs-language-interface-packs-what/</guid><description>For a while I have been curious on how to do Windows OSD with multiple languages &amp;ldquo;the proper way&amp;rdquo; using Configuration Manager. Whenever I have approached the subject I have always felt overwhelmed.
Googling the topic is just a hot mess. You&amp;rsquo;re faced with information that&amp;rsquo;s old, lacking real detail or generally misunderstood. My aim here is to demystify the topic and show you a solid way to do Windows 10 multi language OSD with ConfigMgr along with sound reasoning.</description></item><item><title>ARM (Azure Resource Manager) Templating for Windows Virtual Desktop</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/05/26/arm-azure-resource-manager-templating-for-windows-virtual-desktop/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2020 12:56:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/05/26/arm-azure-resource-manager-templating-for-windows-virtual-desktop/</guid><description>Why would I use ARM templating, isn&amp;rsquo;t the default Image Gallery fine? Well first off, what is ARM Templating? According to Microsoft &amp;ldquo;You can automate deployments and use the practice of infrastructure as code. In code, you define the infrastructure that needs to be deployed. The infrastructure code becomes part of your project. Just like application code, you store the infrastructure code in a source repository and version it&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;
What does all that mean?</description></item><item><title>NET-103 : Layering in Active Directory</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/05/19/net-103-layering-in-active-directory/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/05/19/net-103-layering-in-active-directory/</guid><description>Joe Ravi / CC BY-SA https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0 In previous articles, we&amp;rsquo;ve built the basic services you need without getting too far in the weeds. Now we&amp;rsquo;re going to layer in a central identity service.
It&amp;rsquo;s also hopefully going to be a lot shorter than previous articles, though I can&amp;rsquo;t make any promises - these things tend to all start small, then balloon rapidly.
If you&amp;rsquo;re continuing from NET-102 you&amp;rsquo;ll already have the following machines:</description></item><item><title>Modern Driver Management with the Administration Service</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/05/15/modern-driver-management-with-the-administration-service/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 14:39:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/05/15/modern-driver-management-with-the-administration-service/</guid><description>2021-04-27 update: The solution now works over CMG. Please see this post for details.
Hello!
Today I’d like to share with you a new solution I’ve developed to allow me to use the free Modern Driver Management solution from the team at MSEndpointMgr at my work. My goal is to use the process developed by them for managing drivers in a task sequence and convert it to use the ConfigMgr Administration Service since my company won&amp;rsquo;t allow me to install their third-party web service.</description></item><item><title>Sharing Google Meet Links With Students Safely Can Be Confusing For I.T. Pros, Let Alone Teachers</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/04/26/sharing-google-meet-links-with-students-safely/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 20:26:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/04/26/sharing-google-meet-links-with-students-safely/</guid><description>TL;DR: Classroom-Meet integrated meeting links are safe. Nickname Meet meeting links are safe. Blank/Non-Nickname Meet meeting links ARE NOT safe. Calendar generated Meet meeting links ARE NOT safe. I&amp;rsquo;ll start by saying that I recognize COVID-19 and it&amp;rsquo;s impact on technology use in K-12 public education put many of us in a position of building the airplane as we&amp;rsquo;re flying on it. Administration, Curriculum and Technology have been working hard in school districts around the world to quickly train and support staff and faculty using systems they may never have heard of before this situation.</description></item><item><title>Teams Channel Notification when OSD Fails</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/04/22/teams-channel-notification-when-osd-fails/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/04/22/teams-channel-notification-when-osd-fails/</guid><description>How would you like this lovely notification appearing within MS Teams every time a build failed? Better than getting a helpdesk ticket or not finding out at all.
Well, now you can!
Removed broken screenshot - editor
Step 1 - Configure Teams You need to make sure your O365 Administrator has enabled Incoming webhooks connectors in your O365 Tenant.
Open Teams. Select a channel, or create a new channel specific for these notifications (This is best practice so normal channels are not spammed) Click the &amp;hellip; Next to the channel name and choose Connectors Removed broken screenshot - editor</description></item><item><title>Inventory Deprovisioned Windows 10 Apps</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/03/11/inventory-deprovisioned-windows-10-apps/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2020 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/03/11/inventory-deprovisioned-windows-10-apps/</guid><description>In my previous post I&amp;rsquo;ve shown that we can revert the deprovisioning of Windows 10 apps. This is awesome news for anyone that has removed the Windows Store. I have been unable to find any other way of restoring the Windows Store once it has been deprovisioned, so this is an awesome time saver. Instead of reimaging devices that do not have the store we can simply &amp;lsquo;reprovision&amp;rsquo; the store, and perform a feature update!</description></item><item><title>Managing Multiple Office 365 Deployments with ConfigMgr</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/02/25/managing-multiple-office-365-deployments-with-configmgr/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2020 17:36:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/02/25/managing-multiple-office-365-deployments-with-configmgr/</guid><description>At the client I&amp;rsquo;m currently working for, we have FIVE different deployments of Office 365 Client within Microsoft Enterprise Configuration Manager. The business decided that they only wanted users to have exactly what was needed. Essentially, this is the legacy approach to Office deployment in the MSI days where you could fully customise which components were installed and was easy to add bits back in at a later date.
These are the options they wanted:</description></item><item><title>To Trust Or Not To Trust (UNSIGNED DRIVERS): That Is The Question</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/02/04/to-trust-or-not-to-trust-unsigned-drivers-that-is-the-question/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 06:48:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/02/04/to-trust-or-not-to-trust-unsigned-drivers-that-is-the-question/</guid><description>This post is intended to help others who might want to better understand why their Operating System Deployment (OSD) task sequence (TS) is failing during the Setup Windows and Configuration Manager step with an error code of 0x80004005 and how to identify the unsigned drivers in your driver package that might be causing it. Maybe my google-fu was failing me, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t see anything else out there that was a guided tour with pictures through the old Microsoft article on this issue.</description></item><item><title>Intune/Autopilot Setup Companion Guide Part 2 – Windows Store for Business</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/01/27/intune-autopilot-setup-companion-guide-part-2-windows-store-for-business/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2020 19:15:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/01/27/intune-autopilot-setup-companion-guide-part-2-windows-store-for-business/</guid><description>Purpose The following blog posts will be a companion guide to Steve and Adam’s Intune training videos found at Intune.Training (this covers Episode 3) and will help you get the Windows Store for Business (WSfB, also known as Microsoft Store for Business) setup in your environment. This guide assumes that you already have followed Part 1 of this series and already have a working deployment profile. By the end of this guide you will have access to the Company Portal app and other apps of your choosing.</description></item><item><title>NET-102: Build your lab</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/01/23/net-102-build-your-lab/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2020 07:13:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/01/23/net-102-build-your-lab/</guid><description>Welcome back! We&amp;rsquo;re now going to move on to the actual effort it takes to build your lab. As you recall we got pretty far last time in documenting the beginnings of our network. For this lab I&amp;rsquo;ll be using VMWare Workstation, but you can accomplish this with Microsoft Hyper-V, Oracle VirtualBox, the free tier of VMWare&amp;rsquo;s ESX, or XCP-NG.
If you haven&amp;rsquo;t read the previous post, please have a look here as each post builds upon the last.</description></item><item><title>Windows Virtual Desktop: Creation and Management</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/01/13/wvd-creation-and-management/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 06:33:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/01/13/wvd-creation-and-management/</guid><description>THIS GUIDE IS NOW OUTDATED WITH THE RELEASE OF WVD 2.0, I will create a new blog with the updated info in the future! Some of the info below is still valid! Why Windows Virtual Desktop? Windows Virtual Desktop allows you to create virtual Windows 10 machines that can be accessed from virtually anywhere. This means you can give someone a full desktop experience from virtually anywhere including android and iOS!</description></item><item><title>Reprovision Windows 10 Apps… Wait, What?</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/01/06/reprovision-windows-10-apps-wait-what/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2020 13:54:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/01/06/reprovision-windows-10-apps-wait-what/</guid><description>Remember when we all complained that Microsoft &amp;ldquo;wasn&amp;rsquo;t respecting our app removals!&amp;rdquo; and they were all reinstalled during every feature update? Pepperidge farm remembers. Well, Microsoft was kind enough to hear our collective complaints, and take action on them. That is an awesome quality that we are seeing from the product teams at Microsoft.
Starting in Windows 10 1803, deprovisioned apps will NOT be reinstalled during a feature update. No more Solitaire returning from the dead every time we try to &amp;ldquo;Get current and stay current.</description></item><item><title>NET-101 : Create a Basic Lab Network – Design</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2019/12/17/net-101-create-a-basic-lab-network-design/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2019 06:59:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2019/12/17/net-101-create-a-basic-lab-network-design/</guid><description>As I go through my career, I often find that the answers I take for granted are not easy to find for people who are just starting out. I had the advantage of a dedicated class on network administration to build on, but not everyone had that opportunity. While this article focuses on a lab environment, most of the content will be applicable to real life as well.
I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to include as many reference links as possible to help you learn about the concepts involved, but I cannot explain everything in one article.</description></item></channel></rss>