<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Microsoft on Systems Management Squad</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/tags/microsoft/</link><description>Recent content in Microsoft on Systems Management Squad</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2021 02:10:08 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sysmansquad.com/tags/microsoft/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Microsoft Teams Cache, a burden to us all</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/11/11/microsoft-teams-cache-a-burden-to-us-all/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2021 02:10:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/11/11/microsoft-teams-cache-a-burden-to-us-all/</guid><description>Microsoft Teams Cache, we&amp;rsquo;ve all been there in the last year and a half. Microsoft Teams is working fine, then it&amp;rsquo;s not. What happened? I restarted Teams and it&amp;rsquo;s still acting weird.
Well, Teams is an interesting app when it comes to its cache. It relies heavily on it. I personally do not know all the ins and outs of the Teams cache, but I too know all too well that it is a pain in the butt when it goes awry.</description></item><item><title>Where is the report’s data??</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/05/15/where-is-the-reports-data/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 May 2021 03:21:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/05/15/where-is-the-reports-data/</guid><description>Have you ever looked at a report on a Portal Page and wanted to know just WHERE the data just came from?
Well you can - and finding the information can be so easy. Read on below to see how.
Introduction Take for example this report on a Proactive Remediation. I used one of the built in Proactive Remediations for the example, but it could easily be one of our other Proactive Remediation posts, like Dynamic Outlook Signatures, Building VPN Connections, or Repairing Folder permissions.</description></item><item><title>Find Microsoft Accounts on Company Domains</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/11/23/find-microsoft-accounts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2020/11/23/find-microsoft-accounts/</guid><description>The other day I was helping someone over in the WinAdmins Discord. Their users kept getting confused about what their passwords were, and it was causing a lot of HelpDesk tickets. Let&amp;rsquo;s find out what users have Microsoft accounts on the company domain so we can help move those accounts elsewhere to streamline the user experience.
Update on Prevention: Microsoft has introduced some changes that at least seem to prevent NEW Microsoft Accounts on Company Domains.</description></item><item><title>Managing Multiple Office 365 Deployments with ConfigMgr</title><link>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/02/25/managing-multiple-office-365-deployments-with-configmgr/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2020 17:36:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sysmansquad.com/2021/02/25/managing-multiple-office-365-deployments-with-configmgr/</guid><description>At the client I&amp;rsquo;m currently working for, we have FIVE different deployments of Office 365 Client within Microsoft Enterprise Configuration Manager. The business decided that they only wanted users to have exactly what was needed. Essentially, this is the legacy approach to Office deployment in the MSI days where you could fully customise which components were installed and was easy to add bits back in at a later date.
These are the options they wanted:</description></item></channel></rss>